<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
  <language id="english">
    <entry id="str_inventory_title_journal_page"><![CDATA[Journal Page]]></entry>
    <entry id="str_inventory_description_journal_page"><![CDATA[A snippet from the journal of a doomed expedition.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_0"><![CDATA[A strange note, written on bloody human flesh.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_0"><![CDATA[You examine the ragged piece of flesh, it reeks of sweat and tears.  A series of crude gouges in the skin pulsate and seep blood. They seem to form a pattern! You can just make out the following: "We at Red Hook Games, are deeply grateful for your support and your time spent in the Darkest Dungeon! Good luck in the coming battle..."]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_1"><![CDATA[Journal of Darius, Highwayman (1/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_2"><![CDATA[Journal of Darius, Highwayman (2/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_3"><![CDATA[Journal of Darius, Highwayman (3/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_4"><![CDATA[Journal of Darius, Highwayman (4/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_5"><![CDATA[Journal of Darius, Highwayman (5/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_6"><![CDATA[Journal of Darius, Highwayman (6/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_1"><![CDATA[Day 1 - Rare are travellers on the roads this autumn, and rather than starve I pressed my last coin into the hand of one who dealt in rumours and shadows. Ravens carried cryptic notes that there was a person, or persons who was pledging coin for services best left unmentioned in a hamlet I had never heard of. I am packing to leave immediately.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_2"><![CDATA[Day 4 - The road to this damned hamlet was a tricky one, both to find and to travel. When it revealed its ruined face, I swore I had never seen such neglect, some buildings collapsed, and uncaring residents fidgeting uselessly. I went swiftly to the tavern - others with similar interests had gathered there and I was assembled into an expedition. We leave at first light on the morrow.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_3"><![CDATA[Day 6 - As we travelled from the hamlet, an eerie dread grew. We all felt it but did our best to shrug it off. Sleep was difficult until Raeven, one of my companions, passed me a bitter concoction. The most devout of us, Therion, prayed softly for our safety, superstitious but well intentioned I suppose. I am already falling asleep..]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_4"><![CDATA[Day 7 - We tangled with some unruly louts. Raeven called them cultists. They were ferocious but clumsy.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_5"><![CDATA[Day 8 - Moira has been afflicted with sickness, it must have been some rotting air from a coffin she insisted on piercing with her spade. As terrible as this place is, I know I will not fall for any trap nor crazed idiot. I wager my lucky coin on it.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_6"><![CDATA[My End - I scrawl this, victim of cruel Fortune, who took me up on my wager for I have lost my lucky coin and I now lie helpless as my blood flows swiftly from my ruined body.  My fingers are cold… It was no trap, nor raving cultist that sealed my fate.  We were ambushed by strange undulating shapes, 2 small entities that I cannot hope to describe and a third, much larger beast.  Poor Moira was crushed into a pulp as Therion defended her - he soon lost his arm and his wits left him, “Shambler! Shambler!” he kept shrieking as Raeven yanked him to flee.  I tried to play hero, to buy them a few moments...blew away one of the smaller monsters...last shot...then smashed into the wall...the big one...maybe they made it out...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_7"><![CDATA[The Blackest of Fates (1/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_8"><![CDATA[The Blackest of Fates (2/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_9"><![CDATA[The Blackest of Fates (3/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_10"><![CDATA[The Blackest of Fates (4/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_11"><![CDATA[The Blackest of Fates (5/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_7"><![CDATA[Our purpose was to desecrate their animalistic shrines and thus disperse the swine-folk. But soon we came across an artifact. This was far beyond the crude fetishes crafted by the pig men. It looked as if obsidian had been grown and twisted into a dark symbol of worship. It cradled a pulsing red orb, glowing with malevolent light. Cuthbert, Boleyn and I hesitated, but thrice-damned Mizir, driven by crazed impulse, thrust his torch in a hidden receptacle and thus sealed our fate!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_8"><![CDATA[In that same instant we found ourselves in a place of suffocating dark, facing a creature that defies description and whose recollection causes my quill to jump and shudder! It is merciful only fragments of our battle remain in my psyche... I see Cuthbert hacking at the quivering appendages of the monster. I recall how a piece of its flesh sloughed off and of its own twisted accord sprang onto Boleyn, piercing her stout plate! The occultist, as if to offer himself as tribute was torn apart by its writhing limbs!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_9"><![CDATA[The assault was overwhelming. With Cuthbert slain and as Boleyn fell, I was driven by rage. I leapt and drove my axe into the creature’s many eyes. Purple ichor splashed my face and my very soul shook as it bellowed. The only thing I can recall after was falling swiftly into blackness.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_10"><![CDATA[I now find myself back in the warrens, among the remains of my companions. My wounds are too severe to allow the completion of our - my task. Thus the desecration must resume another time. Curious, there is a ring in my pocket. Where it came from, I cannot begin to guess, though it bears the sigil of the estate’s ancestral owner. Very curious.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_11"><![CDATA[I will return with Cuthbert’s banner and Boleyn’s crossbow so as to honor them with a proper burial. I will leave what is left of thrice-damned Mizir and his trinkets to the swine-folk. Perhaps they will build him the memorial he rightly deserves.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_12"><![CDATA[A Trampled Journal (1/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_13"><![CDATA[A Trampled Journal (2/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_14"><![CDATA[A Trampled Journal (3/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_15"><![CDATA[A Trampled Journal (4/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_12"><![CDATA[Sebastian’s watch was his last. We were jolted during our evening’s repast, the best we could make in these murky halls of our once great house, from the roar and flash of black powder. We dropped our bowls and hurried to him. All we could find was his spent pistol and a trail of blood leading into a maze of shadows. We press on.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_13"><![CDATA[We fought in the East Gallery, filled with portraits of our ancient lineage, uncaring witnesses to the slaughter. Alhazred, the fiery heartbeat of our retinue, wrought keen havoc in our enemy’s ranks. I keenly feel his absence even as I remember voiding myself upon seeing his lifeless body fall, blood pouring from his screaming mouth, some cruel knife having rent his lungs to gore. Yet we were victorious, and thus we press on.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_14"><![CDATA[Hewell, dear friend, exemplary warrior, a survivor of the King’s wars, and many sorties in these halls, met an ignoble end. We were weary, Hewell and I, as we searched for sanctuary. Weariness, it appears, has a murderous streak: it blinded him to the mechanism that tripped the spikes which eviscerated him. I held him as his essence slipped away, another giant fallen in our mad pursuit. I am alone now, weary, but unbowed. I press on.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_15"><![CDATA[I AM BECOME VENGEANCE! All cultists will feel my mace, brigands fear my roar! I am outnumbered, ‘tis true - I am starved and half-mad, but as long as there is breath in my body, I will press on. I will wreak unbearable agony on those who would seek to despoil my great manse! And now they come! I dowse my torch. I DO NOT FEAR THE DARKNESS! THIS IS MY HOUSE, AND WOE TO THE UNINVITED!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_16"><![CDATA[Blood Soaked Pages Torn From A Journal (1/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_17"><![CDATA[Blood Soaked Pages Torn From A Journal (2/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_18"><![CDATA[Blood Soaked Pages Torn From A Journal (3/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_19"><![CDATA[Blood Soaked Pages Torn From A Journal (4/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_20"><![CDATA[Blood Soaked Pages Torn From A Journal (5/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_21"><![CDATA[Blood Soaked Pages Torn From A Journal (6/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_16"><![CDATA[These dark caves drip with an overabundance of humidity, beyond my threshold of comfort. I nearly broke my ankle on the rocks, made slick with some ubiquitous slime. The pools stir and slosh with no visible cause and the shadows beyond torchlight seem to grow and shrink of their own accord.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_17"><![CDATA[My fears are confirmed! With our torch doused by an errant spray of seawater - we were ambushed! Strange fish-like homonids ambushed us in the sudden darkness! The pitch of the torch caught quickly and I glimpsed scaly appendages swinging crude weapons, glistening and barbed. They didn't last long with our torch rekindled. Alas, one bit me on the neck before I gutted it. The wound stings and tingles strangely. Our physic told me to keep it clean and covered...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_18"><![CDATA[The wound is starting to fester. The flesh around it is grey, flaking and ridged, almost scale-like. As I write this, my breathing has taken on a hollow timbre and is more laboured. My compatriots are laughing, and tell me not to worry, it’s just the salt mist in the air that pervades these caverns.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_19"><![CDATA[They are sleeping. I am kept from slumber by a distinct stream of whispers, as if carried by the currents and waves of the sea. I have not told them that most of my flesh has sloughed off, revealing a strange silvery membrane, I keep myself covered. They questioned me when I ate the meat raw at campfall and found my response difficult to understand. I suppose it would be best to explain my condition when they awaken, then they would be convinced of my urgency to leave and find aid in the hamlet.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_20"><![CDATA[The others are gone. They were victims of a malevolent transformation! Their scales had rotted to soft, vulnerable flesh. Slowly suffocating without gills! The worst was their eyes! Close-set, and forced to squint through fleshy slits! I shudder recalling the horrific and unclean warmth of their blood as I rinsed my talons. I nearly retched. May Death grant them soft mercy!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_21"><![CDATA[I cannot recall why we ventured onto land. Why did we leave when Mother Ocean provided all we needed beneath her tender waves? I will now return home, back to Her embrace… [indecipherable scratchings fill the remainder of the page].]]></entry>
  </language>
  <language id="schinese">
    <entry id="str_inventory_title_journal_page"><![CDATA[一页日记]]></entry>
    <entry id="str_inventory_description_journal_page"><![CDATA[描述着一次破灭的探险的日记中的一页]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_0"><![CDATA[一段写在血腥的人肉上的奇怪笔记。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_0"><![CDATA[你们检查了这被撕下的肮脏血肉，它不断散发着汗液和泪水的腥气。一些潦草的刻画在皮肤上渗着血并古怪地搏动着。它们似乎正在形成一个图案！你们还算顺利地拼凑出了这句话：“红勾游戏（Red Hook Games）工作室非常感谢您对‘极暗地牢’投入的大量时间与支持厚爱！祝您下一场战斗好运哦……”]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_1"><![CDATA[强盗大流士的日记（1/6）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_2"><![CDATA[强盗大流士的日记（2/6）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_3"><![CDATA[强盗大流士的日记（3/6）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_4"><![CDATA[强盗大流士的日记（4/6）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_5"><![CDATA[强盗大流士的日记（5/6）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_6"><![CDATA[强盗大流士的日记（6/6）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_1"><![CDATA[第一天 - 这个秋天路上的旅人变得稀少，我饿着肚子把最后的硬币交给了一个消息灵通的人。他的乌鸦带回的神秘纸条指出，在一个我从未听过的村庄，有一个，或一群人在花大价钱请人办事，具体内容不便透露。我马上收拾行李出发了。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_2"><![CDATA[第四天 - 通往这该死村庄的路真是难搞，找起来麻烦，要过去更麻烦。当它终于显出庐山真面目时，我发誓我从未见过如此破败凋零之村庄。在一些倒塌的建筑之间，心不在焉的居民做着无谓的事。我迅速前往了酒馆 - 其他志同道合的人已经在那里集合了。然后我被编入了一支探险队，我们在次日拂晓出发。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_3"><![CDATA[第六天——当我们穿过这个小镇，一种异样的惊恐在我们之中产生了。我们身心俱颤但尽力摆脱着这种感觉。我辗转反侧，直到我的好同伴，瑞文给我了一瓶苦涩的调剂。我们之中最虔诚的人赛润，在我入眠时轻轻地祈求着我们平安无事，这很迷信但我觉得莫名地贴心。我已经快要进入梦乡了……]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_4"><![CDATA[第七天——我们和一些不守规矩的怪人缠斗了一会儿。瑞文对他们嗤之以鼻，称他们“邪教徒”。这些人异乎常人的凶残和狂热，但也挺笨拙的。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_5"><![CDATA[第八天——莫伊拉被病痛折磨着，这一定是在她用铲子撬开棺材时吸入了其中腐败的气体。尽管这个地方是如此糟糕，我决不会因那些所谓的陷阱或那些癫狂的白痴们而死。我以我的幸运币下注。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_6"><![CDATA[我的生命已息——我用手涂抹以书。作为残酷命运的牺牲品，它把我作为赌注带走，因为我已经把我的幸运币弄丢了。现在我就这样无助地躺在这里，任凭血液从我面目全非的身体中缓缓流出。我的指头冰凉……再无陷阱，再无胡言乱语的邪教徒企图诅咒我的命运。我们被怪异、起伏不定的形体所袭击。有两个小的、我难以所述的实体，还有第三个，是一个大得惊人的巨兽。可怜的莫伊拉在赛润保护她前被碾成了肉泥——而赛润也很快地失去了他的手臂和他的胆识，“它跛行着，它蹒跚着！”，当瑞文拽起他逃跑时他就这么一直失神地喃喃傻笑着。而我却不知哪来的勇气逞英雄，为他们争取了一点时间……子弹炸开了其中的一只小的……最后一击……然后被撞进了墙……那只大的……或许他们逃脱……]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_7"><![CDATA[最黑暗的命运（1/5）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_8"><![CDATA[最黑暗的命运（2/5）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_9"><![CDATA[最黑暗的命运（3/5）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_10"><![CDATA[最黑暗的命运（4/5）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_11"><![CDATA[最黑暗的命运（5/5）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_7"><![CDATA[我们任务是摧毁它们粗糙的祭坛，这样猪人就将一哄而散，不再聚集于此地。但是我们很快经过了一个古老造物。这个“祭坛”与猪人搭建的粗制膜拜物差之甚远，它看上去就如同黑曜石为了一个形成一个黑暗的信仰符号而扭曲着生长。它支撑着一个红色的脉动的球体，发着一眼看去就充满邪恶的光。库斯博特、博林和我迟疑着，可就在这时，该千刀万剐的米基尔！他被疯狂冲昏了头，将燃烧的火把刺入“祭坛”来表示他所谓的敬意，也诅咒了我们的命运！]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_8"><![CDATA[就在那一瞬间我们不知怎么就到了一个黑暗得令人窒息的地方，面对着一个我穷尽词语也难能描述的，至今在脑海中令我心思欲裂怪物！理智的帷幕保护了我，只让我的记忆中留下了些许我们战斗的破碎场景。不过我依能想起，那个鬼东西是怎么蜕下一块皮肉，而这块皮肉就这么自己就刺穿了博林的层层铠胄！那个什么“神秘学者”，好似要把自己献祭一般被它起伏扭曲的峰形扯成了碎片！]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_9"><![CDATA[我们完全被压制了。库斯博特与博林先后倒下，我的内心充满了怒火。我全力一跃将我的斧子劈入这怪物的眼睛——许多的眼睛。恶心的紫色脓浆溅了我一脸，我的灵魂则在它咆哮时几近破碎。我最后的记忆是在无尽的黑暗中向下跌落着。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_10"><![CDATA[我如今发现自己倒在肮脏的兽窟间，在我同伴们的遗骸间。我伤势过重，完全不足以完成我们——我的任务。所以这破坏猪人信仰的任务只能等下次完成了。奇怪的是在我的口袋里出现了一枚戒指。这是哪里来的？我毫无头绪，尽管它雕刻着似乎是这片土地拥有者祖辈专用的刻印。真是离奇。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_11"><![CDATA[我将把库斯博特的旗帜与博林的十字弩带回给予薄葬。我将可恶的米基尔的尸骸与他古怪的挂饰留给那些猪人。或许它们会为他今天做出的“贡献”而建造一座纪念碑。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_12"><![CDATA[破灭的日记（1/4）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_13"><![CDATA[破灭的日记（2/4）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_14"><![CDATA[破灭的日记（3/4）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_15"><![CDATA[破灭的日记（4/4）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_12"><![CDATA[塞巴斯蒂安的怀表就是他的遗物了。我们在就餐时被突袭，在本来能在这些原属于我们的黯淡大厅里能够喘一口气的时候；一切在一声咆哮和一抹黑火药的燃光后变了。我们丢下我们的碗向他冲去，而唯一能够找到的是他用过的手枪与一条通向这迷宫那黑暗阴影深处的血迹。我们继续进发。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_13"><![CDATA[我们在东向的画廊遭遇了战斗；画廊满是我们先祖血脉的肖像画，他们以冷漠的眼神见证着这场屠戮。亚尔哈兹瑞德，我们团队最火热的心脏，冲进敌人的队伍如狼似虎。我为他的陨落感到强烈的痛楚，如同我当时不忍目视就这样倒下时的他；鲜血从他尖叫着的嘴中喷涌而出，几把冰冷的刀子深深地扎入了他的肺。然而，胜利依旧属于我们，于是我们继续前进。我们即是火焰。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_14"><![CDATA[赫维尔，我亲爱的老战友，国王战争和在这些走廊中几场袭击的幸存者，却倒在可鄙的诡计之下。我们精疲力竭，赫维尔和我。就在我们寻找一个避难之地时，疲惫，如其所显，揭示了它嗜血的一面：它使赫维尔盲目地踩上了拌子与利刺的机关；机关将他剔得血肉模糊。我在他体液流尽时一直抱着他，又一个巨人倒在我们疯狂的追寻之途中。只剩我一个了，苟延残喘，但是不愿屈服。我要继续。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_15"><![CDATA[我就是复仇之神！！！所有的邪教徒将品尝我的铁锤，匪徒们将在我的怒号中瑟缩！我寡不敌众，真是可笑——我已数日未进粒米，我已经半残半疯，但是只要我还有一口气，我将一直继续。我要把这难忍的痛苦倾泻在那些敢于侵扰我房宅的恶徒身上！哈，他们来了！我熄灭了我的火炬。我才不畏惧这黑暗！！！这是我的房子，那些不受欢迎的东西要倒大霉了！！]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_16"><![CDATA[从日记本撕下的染血一页（1/6）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_17"><![CDATA[从日记本撕下的染血一页（2/6）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_18"><![CDATA[从日记本撕下的染血一页（3/6）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_19"><![CDATA[从日记本撕下的染血一页（4/6）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_20"><![CDATA[从日记本撕下的染血一页（5/6）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_21"><![CDATA[从日记本撕下的染血一页（6/6）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_16"><![CDATA[这些黑暗的洞穴因过度的潮湿不断滴漏着，让我感觉非常不舒服。我几乎在这些湿滑的岩石间扭到了我的脚脖子，那些抬眼即是的黏液使它们更加难以攀爬。那些水洼搅动泼溅，而望去时却空无一物。在火把的光芒下的影绰仿佛活了一样，令人不安地生长着、退缩着。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_17"><![CDATA[我的恐惧成真了！我们的火把被突如其来的浪花熄灭——我们被围了！这些活物有人猿般的特征，但却有一颗鱼的头；这些水栖的恶物在聒噪声中同黑暗一起突然向我们袭来！我一把抓住跌落的火把，在那瞬间我瞥见了带鳞肢体挥舞着的，在波光映衬之下锋利而多刺的简陋武器。它们在我们重新点燃火把后没撑多久。咳，其中有个家伙在我将它开膛破肚之前咬在了我的脖子上。伤口出奇的刺痛。我们的医生让我将之清洗干净后仔细包扎起来……]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_18"><![CDATA[脖子上的伤口开始溃烂了。在腐臭的水潭边，我看到创口周围的血肉发灰起皱，一片片脱落，令人不安地像极了鳞片；就在我写下这些时，我吃力地呼吸着，肺部发着空洞的回响。我的同伴笑着让我不要担心，这只是因为我吸多了弥漫在这些水窟中的盐雾罢了。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_19"><![CDATA[他们都睡着了。而我却因为古怪、低语般的水流声了无睡意，就好像我正被洋流海潮轻轻托起。我没敢告诉他们我伤口周围的组织已腐殒殆尽，而一层奇怪的银色薄膜却显露了出来；我把这些遮得严严实实。他们刚刚还在营火熄灭后惊讶地发现我啃着生肉，而我模糊不清的嗓音不足以回答他们的质问。我觉得等他们醒来之后我最好仔细解释一下我的状况，或许他们就会相信这问题的严重性，离开这个鬼地方，到小镇里寻找援助。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_20"><![CDATA[其他人都逝世了。他们都是那可怕异变的受害者！他们的鳞因腐败化作了绵软，脆弱的肉。他们因没有鳃窒息着！他们的眼睛犹如噩梦！那被增生的肉帘囚禁，挣扎在阻塞物中奄奄一息的明眸！在洗净手蹼时，萦绕我心头的尽是他们可怕、瘟热的血液……我几乎吐了出来。愿死亡能结束他们的长久的苦难！]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_21"><![CDATA[我都不记得我们为甚要冒这么大险来到陆地上。为什么我们要在大海母亲提供了一切所需与安宁时离开它温柔的波涛？我的同伴们都在折磨与凄苦中安息，我已经无力继续到陆地的征程。现在我要回家，回到大海的怀抱……［不可读的划刻痕迹将纸页剩下的部分挤满］]]></entry>
  </language>
</root>