<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
  <language id="english">
    <entry id="str_inventory_title_journal_page"><![CDATA[Journal Page]]></entry>
    <entry id="str_inventory_description_journal_page"><![CDATA[A snippet from the journal of a doomed expedition.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_0"><![CDATA[A strange note, written on bloody human flesh.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_0"><![CDATA[You examine the ragged piece of flesh, it reeks of sweat and tears.  A series of crude gouges in the skin pulsate and seep blood. They seem to form a pattern! You can just make out the following: "We at Red Hook Games, are deeply grateful for your support and your time spent in the Darkest Dungeon! Good luck in the coming battle..."]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_1"><![CDATA[Journal of Darius, Highwayman (1/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_2"><![CDATA[Journal of Darius, Highwayman (2/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_3"><![CDATA[Journal of Darius, Highwayman (3/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_4"><![CDATA[Journal of Darius, Highwayman (4/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_5"><![CDATA[Journal of Darius, Highwayman (5/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_6"><![CDATA[Journal of Darius, Highwayman (6/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_1"><![CDATA[Day 1 - Rare are travellers on the roads this autumn, and rather than starve I pressed my last coin into the hand of one who dealt in rumours and shadows. Ravens carried cryptic notes that there was a person, or persons who was pledging coin for services best left unmentioned in a hamlet I had never heard of. I am packing to leave immediately.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_2"><![CDATA[Day 4 - The road to this damned hamlet was a tricky one, both to find and to travel. When it revealed its ruined face, I swore I had never seen such neglect, some buildings collapsed, and uncaring residents fidgeting uselessly. I went swiftly to the tavern - others with similar interests had gathered there and I was assembled into an expedition. We leave at first light on the morrow.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_3"><![CDATA[Day 6 - As we travelled from the hamlet, an eerie dread grew. We all felt it but did our best to shrug it off. Sleep was difficult until Raeven, one of my companions, passed me a bitter concoction. The most devout of us, Therion, prayed softly for our safety, superstitious but well intentioned I suppose. I am already falling asleep..]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_4"><![CDATA[Day 7 - We tangled with some unruly louts. Raeven called them cultists. They were ferocious but clumsy.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_5"><![CDATA[Day 8 - Moira has been afflicted with sickness, it must have been some rotting air from a coffin she insisted on piercing with her spade. As terrible as this place is, I know I will not fall for any trap nor crazed idiot. I wager my lucky coin on it.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_6"><![CDATA[My End - I scrawl this, victim of cruel Fortune, who took me up on my wager for I have lost my lucky coin and I now lie helpless as my blood flows swiftly from my ruined body.  My fingers are cold… It was no trap, nor raving cultist that sealed my fate.  We were ambushed by strange undulating shapes, 2 small entities that I cannot hope to describe and a third, much larger beast.  Poor Moira was crushed into a pulp as Therion defended her - he soon lost his arm and his wits left him, “Shambler! Shambler!” he kept shrieking as Raeven yanked him to flee.  I tried to play hero, to buy them a few moments...blew away one of the smaller monsters...last shot...then smashed into the wall...the big one...maybe they made it out...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_7"><![CDATA[The Blackest of Fates (1/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_8"><![CDATA[The Blackest of Fates (2/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_9"><![CDATA[The Blackest of Fates (3/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_10"><![CDATA[The Blackest of Fates (4/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_11"><![CDATA[The Blackest of Fates (5/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_7"><![CDATA[Our purpose was to desecrate their animalistic shrines and thus disperse the swine-folk. But soon we came across an artifact. This was far beyond the crude fetishes crafted by the pig men. It looked as if obsidian had been grown and twisted into a dark symbol of worship. It cradled a pulsing red orb, glowing with malevolent light. Cuthbert, Boleyn and I hesitated, but thrice-damned Mizir, driven by crazed impulse, thrust his torch in a hidden receptacle and thus sealed our fate!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_8"><![CDATA[In that same instant we found ourselves in a place of suffocating dark, facing a creature that defies description and whose recollection causes my quill to jump and shudder! It is merciful only fragments of our battle remain in my psyche... I see Cuthbert hacking at the quivering appendages of the monster. I recall how a piece of its flesh sloughed off and of its own twisted accord sprang onto Boleyn, piercing her stout plate! The occultist, as if to offer himself as tribute was torn apart by its writhing limbs!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_9"><![CDATA[The assault was overwhelming. With Cuthbert slain and as Boleyn fell, I was driven by rage. I leapt and drove my axe into the creature’s many eyes. Purple ichor splashed my face and my very soul shook as it bellowed. The only thing I can recall after was falling swiftly into blackness.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_10"><![CDATA[I now find myself back in the warrens, among the remains of my companions. My wounds are too severe to allow the completion of our - my task. Thus the desecration must resume another time. Curious, there is a ring in my pocket. Where it came from, I cannot begin to guess, though it bears the sigil of the estate’s ancestral owner. Very curious.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_11"><![CDATA[I will return with Cuthbert’s banner and Boleyn’s crossbow so as to honor them with a proper burial. I will leave what is left of thrice-damned Mizir and his trinkets to the swine-folk. Perhaps they will build him the memorial he rightly deserves.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_12"><![CDATA[A Trampled Journal (1/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_13"><![CDATA[A Trampled Journal (2/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_14"><![CDATA[A Trampled Journal (3/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_15"><![CDATA[A Trampled Journal (4/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_12"><![CDATA[Sebastian’s watch was his last. We were jolted during our evening’s repast, the best we could make in these murky halls of our once great house, from the roar and flash of black powder. We dropped our bowls and hurried to him. All we could find was his spent pistol and a trail of blood leading into a maze of shadows. We press on.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_13"><![CDATA[We fought in the East Gallery, filled with portraits of our ancient lineage, uncaring witnesses to the slaughter. Alhazred, the fiery heartbeat of our retinue, wrought keen havoc in our enemy’s ranks. I keenly feel his absence even as I remember voiding myself upon seeing his lifeless body fall, blood pouring from his screaming mouth, some cruel knife having rent his lungs to gore. Yet we were victorious, and thus we press on.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_14"><![CDATA[Hewell, dear friend, exemplary warrior, a survivor of the King’s wars, and many sorties in these halls, met an ignoble end. We were weary, Hewell and I, as we searched for sanctuary. Weariness, it appears, has a murderous streak: it blinded him to the mechanism that tripped the spikes which eviscerated him. I held him as his essence slipped away, another giant fallen in our mad pursuit. I am alone now, weary, but unbowed. I press on.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_15"><![CDATA[I AM BECOME VENGEANCE! All cultists will feel my mace, brigands fear my roar! I am outnumbered, ‘tis true - I am starved and half-mad, but as long as there is breath in my body, I will press on. I will wreak unbearable agony on those who would seek to despoil my great manse! And now they come! I dowse my torch. I DO NOT FEAR THE DARKNESS! THIS IS MY HOUSE, AND WOE TO THE UNINVITED!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_16"><![CDATA[Blood Soaked Pages Torn From A Journal (1/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_17"><![CDATA[Blood Soaked Pages Torn From A Journal (2/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_18"><![CDATA[Blood Soaked Pages Torn From A Journal (3/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_19"><![CDATA[Blood Soaked Pages Torn From A Journal (4/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_20"><![CDATA[Blood Soaked Pages Torn From A Journal (5/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_21"><![CDATA[Blood Soaked Pages Torn From A Journal (6/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_16"><![CDATA[These dark caves drip with an overabundance of humidity, beyond my threshold of comfort. I nearly broke my ankle on the rocks, made slick with some ubiquitous slime. The pools stir and slosh with no visible cause and the shadows beyond torchlight seem to grow and shrink of their own accord.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_17"><![CDATA[My fears are confirmed! With our torch doused by an errant spray of seawater - we were ambushed! Strange fish-like homonids ambushed us in the sudden darkness! The pitch of the torch caught quickly and I glimpsed scaly appendages swinging crude weapons, glistening and barbed. They didn't last long with our torch rekindled. Alas, one bit me on the neck before I gutted it. The wound stings and tingles strangely. Our physic told me to keep it clean and covered...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_18"><![CDATA[The wound is starting to fester. The flesh around it is grey, flaking and ridged, almost scale-like. As I write this, my breathing has taken on a hollow timbre and is more laboured. My compatriots are laughing, and tell me not to worry, it’s just the salt mist in the air that pervades these caverns.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_19"><![CDATA[They are sleeping. I am kept from slumber by a distinct stream of whispers, as if carried by the currents and waves of the sea. I have not told them that most of my flesh has sloughed off, revealing a strange silvery membrane, I keep myself covered. They questioned me when I ate the meat raw at campfall and found my response difficult to understand. I suppose it would be best to explain my condition when they awaken, then they would be convinced of my urgency to leave and find aid in the hamlet.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_20"><![CDATA[The others are gone. They were victims of a malevolent transformation! Their scales had rotted to soft, vulnerable flesh. Slowly suffocating without gills! The worst was their eyes! Close-set, and forced to squint through fleshy slits! I shudder recalling the horrific and unclean warmth of their blood as I rinsed my talons. I nearly retched. May Death grant them soft mercy!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_21"><![CDATA[I cannot recall why we ventured onto land. Why did we leave when Mother Ocean provided all we needed beneath her tender waves? I will now return home, back to Her embrace… [indecipherable scratchings fill the remainder of the page].]]></entry>
  </language>
  <language id="french">
    <entry id="str_inventory_title_journal_page"><![CDATA[Page de journal]]></entry>
    <entry id="str_inventory_description_journal_page"><![CDATA[Une bribe du journal d'une expédition condamnée.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_0"><![CDATA[Une note étrange, rédigée sur de la peau humaine sanguinolente.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_0"><![CDATA[Vous examinez le morceau de chair déchiqueté, il pue la sueur et les larmes. Une série d'entailles grossières dans la peau pulse et saigne. Elles semblent former un motif ! Vous arrivez juste à déchiffrer ce qui suit : « Nous, Red Hook Games, vous sommes profondément reconnaissants de votre soutien et du temps passé dans le Donjon Ténébreux ! Bonne chance pour la bataille à venir... »]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_1"><![CDATA[Journal de Darius, bandit de grand chemin (1/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_2"><![CDATA[Journal de Darius, bandit de grand chemin (2/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_3"><![CDATA[Journal de Darius, bandit de grand chemin (3/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_4"><![CDATA[Journal de Darius, bandit de grand chemin (4/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_5"><![CDATA[Journal de Darius, bandit de grand chemin (5/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_6"><![CDATA[Journal de Darius, bandit de grand chemin (6/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_1"><![CDATA[Jour 1 - Cet automne les voyageurs se font rares sur les routes, aussi, plutôt que de mourir de faim, j'ai remis ma dernière pièce entre les mains d'un pourvoyeur de rumeurs et d'ombres. Les corbeaux transportaient des notes mystérieuses sur une personne, ou plusieurs personnes, prêtes à payer contre des services à ne pas ébruiter, dans un Hameau dont je n'ai jamais entendu parler. Je me prépare à partir immédiatement.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_2"><![CDATA[Jour 4 - La route vers ce maudit Hameau fut difficile à trouver comme à parcourir. Lorsqu'il apparut dans toute sa ruine, je jure que je n'avais jamais rien vu d'aussi abandonné. Certains bâtiments s'étaient effondrés et des habitants indifférents s'agitaient sans but. Je me rendis rapidement à la taverne où d'autres avec des intérêts similaires s'étaient rassemblés, et je fus intégré à l'expédition. Nous partons demain à l'aube.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_3"><![CDATA[Jour 6 - En quittant le Hameau, une terreur sinistre grandit. Nous la ressentîmes tous mais fîmes de notre mieux pour l'ignorer. Le sommeil me fuyait jusqu'à ce que Raeven, l'un de mes compagnons, me passe une décoction amère. Le plus pieux d'entre nous, Therion, pria tout bas pour notre sécurité, superstitieux mais de bonne volonté, je pense. Je m'endors déjà...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_4"><![CDATA[Jour 7 - Nous avons eu des démêlées avec un groupe désorganisé. Raeven les appelle des adeptes. Féroces, mais maladroits.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_5"><![CDATA[Jour 8 - Moira est tombée malade, sûrement à cause de l'air vicié d'un cercueil qu'elle a voulu à tout prix percer de son épée. Aussi terrible que soit ce lieu, je sais que je ne périrai pas dans un piège ni de la main d'un imbécile dément. Je parie ma pièce porte-bonheur là-dessus.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_6"><![CDATA[Ma Fin - j'écris ceci, victime de la cruelle Fortune qui m'a pris au mot, car j'ai perdu ma pièce fétiche et je gis désormais sans défense, mon sang coulant à gros bouillons de mon corps dévasté. Mes doigts sont froids… Mon destin n'a été scellé ni par un piège ou un adepte dément. Nous avons été pris en embuscade par des formes étranges et ondulantes, 2 petites entités que je n'ose décrire et une troisième bête bien plus grande. La pauvre Moira a été réduite en bouillie alors que Therion la défendait. Il a rapidement perdu un bras et sa raison, « L'Ombre ! L'Ombre ! » hurlait-il sans cesse alors que Raeven le tirait pour s'enfuir. J'ai tenté de jouer les héros, pour leur faire gagner un peu de temps... détruis l'un des plus petits monstres... dernier tir... puis écrasé contre le mur... le grand... ils s'en sont peut-être sortis...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_7"><![CDATA[Le plus sombre des destins (1/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_8"><![CDATA[Le plus sombre des destins (2/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_9"><![CDATA[Le plus sombre des destins (3/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_10"><![CDATA[Le plus sombre des destins (4/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_11"><![CDATA[Le plus sombre des destins (5/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_7"><![CDATA[Notre but était de profaner leurs sanctuaires bestiaux et ainsi de disperser le peuple porcin. Mais nous avons vite trouvé un artefact. C'était de loin le fétiche le plus grossier fabriqué par les porcins. On aurait dit de l'obsidienne élevée et tordue en un symbole d'adoration ténébreux. Il abritait un orbe rouge battant, qui brillait d'une lumière malsaine. Cuthbert, Boleyn et moi hésitâmes mais ce triple damné de Mizir, poussé par une impulsion démente, enfonça sa torche dans un réceptacle caché et scella ainsi notre sort !]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_8"><![CDATA[En un instant nous nous trouvâmes dans un lieu à la noirceur suffocante, faisant face à une créature qui défie toute description et dont le souvenir suffit à faire trembler ma plume ! Par chance, mon esprit n'a gardé que des fragments de notre bataille... Je vois Cuthbert tranchant les appendices frémissants du monstre. Je me souviens comment un morceau de chair se détacha de sa propre volonté pour sauter sur Boleyn, perçant son épais plastron ! L'occultiste fut écartelé par ses propres membres tordus, comme s'il s'offrait en sacrifice !]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_9"><![CDATA[L'attaque fut renversante. Cuthbert abattu et Boleyn tombée, je fus pris de rage. Je bondis et enfonçai ma hache dans les nombreux yeux de la créature. Un ichor violet éclaboussa mon visage et mon âme fut ébranlée par ses hurlements. La seule chose dont je me souviens ensuite, c'est d'avoir perdu connaissance.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_10"><![CDATA[Je me retrouve maintenant dans les Tanières, près des cadavres de mes compagnons. Mes blessures sont trop sévères pour terminer notre... ma tâche. Mais la profanation devra reprendre plus tard. Curieusement, j'ai un anneau dans ma poche. Je n'arrive pas à deviner d'où il peut bien venir mais il porte le sceau du propriétaire ancestral du domaine. Vraiment étrange.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_11"><![CDATA[Je vais revenir avec la bannière de Cuthbert et l'arbalète de Boleyn afin de leur rendre honneur lors d'un enterrement dans les règles. Je vais laisser ce triple damné de Mizir et ses breloques au peuple porcin. Ils lui bâtiront peut-être le mémorial qu'il mérite.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_12"><![CDATA[Un journal piétiné (1/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_13"><![CDATA[Un journal piétiné (2/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_14"><![CDATA[Un journal piétiné (3/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_15"><![CDATA[Un journal piétiné (4/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_12"><![CDATA[Le tour de garde de Sebastian fut son dernier. Nous fûmes tirés de notre souper, cuisiné au mieux dans les salles sombres de notre maison autrefois grandiose, par le fracas et l'éclair de la poudre. Lâchant nos bols, nous nous précipitâmes vers lui. Nous ne trouvâmes que son pistolet déchargé et une traînée de sang menant à un labyrinthe de ténèbres. Nous repartons.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_13"><![CDATA[Nous combattîmes dans la galerie remplie des portraits de nos ancêtres, témoins insensibles du massacre. Alhazred, l'âme passionnée de notre cortège, sema le chaos dans les rangs de l'ennemi. Je ressens fortement son absence alors que je me souviens avoir fait le vide en voyant tomber son corps sans vie, du sang coulant de sa bouche béante après qu'un couteau cruel lui ait déchiqueté les poumons. Mais nous avons vaincu et donc nous continuons.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_14"><![CDATA[Hewell, cher ami, guerrier exemplaire, survivant des guerres royales et de moult sorties en ces salles, a rencontré une fin ignoble. Nous étions harassé, Hewell et moi, et cherchions un refuge. La fatigue a semble-t-il un côté meurtrier : il ne vit pas le mécanisme qui déclencha les piques qui l'éventrèrent. Je le tins alors qu'il agonisait, autre géant tombé dans notre folle poursuite. Désormais je suis seul, épuisé mais insoumis. J'avance.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_15"><![CDATA[JE SUIS DEVENU VENGEANCE ! Adeptes, sentez le poids de ma masse, brigands craignez mon rugissement ! Je suis en infériorité numérique, c'est vrai. Je suis affamé et à moitié fou, mais tant qu'il me restera un souffle de vie, j'avancerai. J'offrirai une agonie insupportable à ceux qui chercheront à me dépouiller de ma demeure ! Les voici ! J'éteins ma torche. JE NE CRAINS PAS LES TÉNÈBRES ! CECI EST MA MAISON, MALHEUR AUX INTRUS !]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_16"><![CDATA[Pages de journal imbibées de sang (1/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_17"><![CDATA[Pages de journal imbibées de sang (2/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_18"><![CDATA[Pages de journal imbibées de sang (3/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_19"><![CDATA[Pages de journal imbibées de sang (4/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_20"><![CDATA[Pages de journal imbibées de sang (5/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_21"><![CDATA[Pages de journal imbibées de sang (6/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_16"><![CDATA[Ces grottes sombres ruissellent d'humidité, trop pour m'être confortable. Je me suis presque brisé la cheville sur les rochers rendus glissants par un mucus omniprésent. Les flaques bougent et refluent sans cause visible et les ombres au-delà des torches semblent grandir et rapetisser de leur propre fait.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_17"><![CDATA[Mes craintes ont été confirmées ! Nos torches éteintes par des embruns, nous avons subi une attaque surprise ! Une embuscade tendue dans le noir par des sortes d'hommes-poissons ! La poix de la torche prit rapidement et j'entrevis des appendices écailleux maniant des armes grossières, luisantes et dentelées. Ils ne tinrent pas longtemps une fois la torche rallumée. Hélas, un d'entre eux réussit à me mordre avant que je l'éventre. La blessure picote étrangement. Notre médecin m'a dit de garder la blessure propre et couverte...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_18"><![CDATA[La blessure commence à s'infecter. La chair autour est grise, pelée et ridée, presque écailleuse. Alors que j'écris ceci, ma respiration devient plus caverneuse et difficile. Mes compatriotes rient, et me disent de ne pas m'inquiéter, que c'est juste l'air salé qui envahit ces cavernes.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_19"><![CDATA[Ils dorment. Je n'arrive pas à sombrer à cause d'un flux distinct de murmures, comme porté par les courants marins et les vagues. Je ne leur ai pas dit que presque toute ma chair est tombée, révélant une étrange membrane argentée, je ne me découvre pas. Ils m'ont posé des questions quand j'ai mangé ma viande crue au camp et ont eu du mal à comprendre ma réponse. Je suppose qu'il vaudrait mieux que je leur explique mon état à leur réveil, ainsi ils seraient convaincu de ma hâte à partir et à aller trouver de l'aide au Hameau.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_20"><![CDATA[Les autres sont partis. Ils ont subi une transformation malsaine ! Leurs écailles ont pourri en une chair molle et vulnérable. Suffoquant lentement sans leurs branchies ! Le pire était leurs yeux ! Fermés, et forcés de loucher par des fentes dans la chair ! Je tremble au souvenir de la chaleur horrible et malsaine de leur sang alors que je rinçais mes griffes. J'ai failli vomir. Puisse la mort leur accorder une douce pitié !]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_21"><![CDATA[Je ne me souviens plus pourquoi je me suis aventuré sur la terre ferme. Pourquoi sommes-nous partis quand Mère océan fournit tout ce dont nous avons besoin sous ses tendres vagues ? Je vais rentrer chez moi, à ses cotés… [des griffonnages indéchiffrables remplissent le reste de la page].]]></entry>
  </language>
  <language id="german">
    <entry id="str_inventory_title_journal_page"><![CDATA[Tagebuchseite]]></entry>
    <entry id="str_inventory_description_journal_page"><![CDATA[Ein Auszug aus dem Tagebuch einer dem Untergang geweihten Expedition.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_0"><![CDATA[Eine seltsame Notiz, geschrieben auf blutigem Menschenfleisch.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_0"><![CDATA[Du untersuchst das zerfetzte Stück Fleisch. Es stinkt nach Schweiß und Tränen. Eine Reihe grober Einschnitte in der Haut pulsieren und tropfen vor Blut. Sie scheinen ein Muster zu ergeben! Du kannst Folgendes lesen: „Wir bei Red Hook Games sind zutiefst dankbar für deine Unterstützung und die Zeit, die du mit Darkest Dungeon verbracht hast! Viel Glück in der kommenden Schlacht ...”]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_1"><![CDATA[Tagebuch von Darius, dem Wegelagerer (1/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_2"><![CDATA[Tagebuch von Darius, dem Wegelagerer (2/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_3"><![CDATA[Tagebuch von Darius, dem Wegelagerer (3/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_4"><![CDATA[Tagebuch von Darius, dem Wegelagerer (4/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_5"><![CDATA[Tagebuch von Darius, dem Wegelagerer (5/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_6"><![CDATA[Tagebuch von Darius, dem Wegelagerer (6/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_1"><![CDATA[1. Tag – Es gibt in diesem Herbst kaum Reisende auf den Straßen. Anstatt zu verhungern, drückte ich meine letzte Münze jemandem in die Hand, der mit Gerüchten und Schatten handelt. Raben trugen mysteriöse Briefe heran. Darin war von einer oder mehreren Personen die Rede, die Münzen für Dienste versprechen, welche unerwähnt bleiben sollten – in irgendeinem Dorf, von dem ich noch nie gehört habe. Ich mache mich sofort auf den Weg.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_2"><![CDATA[4. Tag – Der Weg in dieses vermaledeite Dorf war nicht nur schwer zu finden, sondern auch äußerst beschwerlich. Als ich ankam, machte das Dorf einen völlig heruntergekommenen und verwahrlosten Eindruck, wie ich ihn noch nie erlebt hatte. Einige Gebäude waren eingestürzt, und die gleichgültigen Bewohner streunten nutzlos durch die Gegend. Ich ging sofort in die Taverne – dort hatten sich andere mit ähnlichen Interessen versammelt, und ich wurde einer Expedition zugeteilt. Wir werden im Morgengrauen aufbrechen.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_3"><![CDATA[6. Tag – Als wir vom Dorf aufbrachen, beschlich uns ein unheimliches Gefühl. Wir verspürten es alle, aber gaben unser Bestes, es abzuschütteln. Das Schlafen fällt mir schwer, aber Raeven, einer meiner Kameraden, gab mir einen bitteren Trank. Therion, der Gottesfürchtigste von uns, betete für unsere Sicherheit. Abergläubischer Humbug mit guten Absichten, denke ich. Ich kann kaum mehr die Augen offenhalten ...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_4"><![CDATA[7. Tag – Wir hatten eine Keilerei mit ein paar unbändigen Flegeln. Raeven nannte sie Kultisten. Sie kämpften wild, aber ungeschickt.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_5"><![CDATA[8. Tag – Mira wird von einer Krankheit geplagt. Wahrscheinlich verursacht durch die üblen Dünste, die aus einem Sarg austraten, den sie unbedingt mit ihrem Spaten aufstemmen musste. Es ist hier zwar ziemlich schaurig, aber ich werde mich von nichts und niemandem hinters Licht führen lassen. Darauf wette ich meine Glücksmünze ...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_6"><![CDATA[Mein Ende naht ... das Ungemach scheint sich auf meine Wette eingelassen zu haben, denn meine Glücksmünze bin ich los. Jetzt liege ich hilflos hier, und das Blut strömt aus meinem geschundenen Körper. Meine Finger sind kalt ... Es waren keine Fallen oder zeternden Kultisten, die mein Schicksal besiegelten. Wir wurden von seltsamen, sich windenden Wesen angegriffen – zwei kleinere Gestalten, die ich unmöglich beschreiben kann, und eine dritte, weitaus größere Bestie. Die arme Mira wurde zu Brei geschlagen ... Therion versuchte, sie zu verteidigen, aber verlor schnell seinen Arm, und kurz darauf auch seinen Verstand. „Schlurfer, Schlurfer!“, schrie er, während Raeven ihn zur Flucht drängte. Ich wollte den Helden spielen und ihnen einen Vorsprung verschaffen ... ich pustete eins der kleineren Monster um ... es war mein letzter Schuss ... das große Monster schleuderte mich gegen eine Wand ... ich hoffe, sie konnten entkommen ...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_7"><![CDATA[Das schwärzeste Schicksal (1/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_8"><![CDATA[Das schwärzeste Schicksal (2/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_9"><![CDATA[Das schwärzeste Schicksal (3/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_10"><![CDATA[Das schwärzeste Schicksal (4/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_11"><![CDATA[Das schwärzeste Schicksal (5/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_7"><![CDATA[Unsere Mission war es, ihre animalischen Schreine zu entweihen und diese Schweinemenschen zu vertreiben. Aber dann stießen wir auf ein Artefakt, das die kruden Fetische der Schweinemenschen weit übertraf. Es sah aus, als wäre Obsidian zu einem finsteren Symbol der Anbetung geformt worden. Der Stein umgab eine pulsierende, rote Kugel, die ein niederträchtiges Licht ausstrahlte. Cuthbert, Boleyn und ich zögerten – aber dann steckte der dreifach vermaledeite Mizir in einer wahnwitzigen Anwandlung seine Fackel in ein verborgenes Gefäß, und unser Schicksal war besiegelt!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_8"><![CDATA[Sogleich fanden wir uns in einer erstickenden Dunkelheit wieder – und sahen uns einer Kreatur gegenüber, die jeglicher Beschreibung spottet, und deren Angedenken meine Feder erzittern lässt! Zum Glück kann ich mich nur an Bruchteile unseres Kampfes erinnern ... Cuthbert hackte auf die zuckenden Fortsätze des Monsters ein. Ich erinnere mich, wie ein Stück des Fleisches sich löste, eigenständig Boleyn ansprang und ihren kräftigen Plattenpanzer durchbohrte! Der Okkultist wollte sich scheinbar als Opfer anbieten, wurde aber von den sich windenden Gliedmaßen des Monsters in Stücke gerissen!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_9"><![CDATA[Der Angriff war überwältigend. Cuthbert lag schon erschlagen da, und als auch Boleyn fiel, überkam mich ein heftiger Zorn. Ich sprang vor und trieb meine Axt in eins der vielen Augen der Kreatur. Purpurfarbener Schleim ergoss sich über mein Gesicht, und das Monster brüllte auf, dass es meine Seele erschütterte. Danach kann ich mich nur noch erinnern, wie mir schwarz vor Augen wurde ...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_10"><![CDATA[Nun finde ich mich im Labyrinth wieder, zwischen den Gebeinen meiner Kameraden. Meine Wunden sind zu schwerwiegend, um unsere ... um meine Aufgabe abzuschließen. Mit der Entweihung muss es also ein anderes Mal weitergehen. Seltsamerweise befindet sich ein Ring in meiner Tasche. Ich kann nur vermuten, woher er stammt – aber er trägt das Siegel des Vorfahren, dem das Anwesen gehörte. Wirklich sehr seltsam.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_11"><![CDATA[Ich werde mit Cuthberts Banner und Boleyns Armbrust zurückkehren und ihnen ein anständiges Begräbnis zukommen lassen. Was den dreifach vermaledeiten Mizir angeht, so überlasse ich ihn und seine Accessoires den Schweinemenschen. Vielleicht bauen sie ihm ja ein Denkmal, wie es seiner würdig wäre.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_12"><![CDATA[Ein zertrampeltes Tagebuch (1/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_13"><![CDATA[Ein zertrampeltes Tagebuch (2/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_14"><![CDATA[Ein zertrampeltes Tagebuch (3/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_15"><![CDATA[Ein zertrampeltes Tagebuch (4/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_12"><![CDATA[Sebastians Wache war seine letzte. Als wir bei der Abendmahlzeit saßen (der besten, die wir in den düsteren Hallen unseres einst prachtvollen Hauses zubereiten konnten) wurden wir von donnernden Schüssen aufgeschreckt. Wir ließen unsere Schüsseln fallen und eilten zu ihm. Wir fanden nur seine leere Pistole und eine Blutspur, die in ein Labyrinth aus Schatten führte. Wir geben nicht auf.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_13"><![CDATA[Wir kämpften in der Ostgalerie, die von Portraits unserer Ahnen geziert wird – gleichgültige Zeugen des Gemetzels. Alhazred, der feurige Lebensfunke unseres Gefolges, stiftete Chaos in den feindlichen Reihen. Sein Tod schmerzt sehr, und ich erinnere mich, dass mir unheimlich elend wurde, als ich seinen leblosen Körper fallen sah. Blut strömte aus einem schreienden Mund, nachdem ein heimtückisches Messer seine Lungen grausam zerfetzt hatte. Nichtsdestotrotz trugen wir den Sieg davon und kämpfen weiter.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_14"><![CDATA[Hewell, ein guter Freund, ein vorbildlicher Krieger, ein Überlebender der Königskriege und vieler Einsätze in diesen Gemäuern, fand ein schändliches Ende. Hewell und ich waren kampfesmüde und suchten nach einer Zuflucht. Nun scheint die Müdigkeit eine mörderische Seite zu haben: er übersah einen Mechanismus, der die Stacheln auslöste, die ihn in Stücke schnitten. Ich hielt ihn in meinen Armen, als seine Seele ihren Körper verließ ... ein weiterer gefallener Held in unserem wahnsinnigen Streben. Nun bin ich ganz alleine – müde, aber ungebeugt. Ich gehe weiter.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_15"><![CDATA[ICH BIN DIE PERSONIFIZIERTE RACHE! Alle Kultisten werden meine Keule zu spüren bekommen. Briganten, fürchtet mein Gebrüll! Wahrlich, ich bin in der Unterzahl, halb verhungert und halb verrückt – aber solange ich noch atme, solange kämpfe ich weiter. Ich werde allen unerträgliche Qualen zufügen, die es darauf abgesehen haben, mein prachtvolles Pfarrhaus zu plündern! Und da kommen sie nun! Ich lösche meine Fackel. ICH HABE KEINE ANGST VOR DER DUNKELHEIT! DIES IST MEIN HAUS! WEHE DEN UNGEBETENEN BESUCHERN!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_16"><![CDATA[Blutgetränkte, herausgerissene Seiten eines Tagebuchs (1/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_17"><![CDATA[Blutgetränkte, herausgerissene Seiten eines Tagebuchs (2/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_18"><![CDATA[Blutgetränkte, herausgerissene Seiten eines Tagebuchs (3/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_19"><![CDATA[Blutgetränkte, herausgerissene Seiten eines Tagebuchs (4/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_20"><![CDATA[Blutgetränkte, herausgerissene Seiten eines Tagebuchs (5/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_21"><![CDATA[Blutgetränkte, herausgerissene Seiten eines Tagebuchs (6/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_16"><![CDATA[Diese dunklen Höhlen triefen vor Feuchtigkeit, und es ist unerträglich. Ich hätte mir fast den Fuß gebrochen, als ich auf den mit Schleim bedeckten Steinen ausrutschte. Die Becken blubbern und schwappen ohne ersichtlichen Grund, und die Schatten jenseits des Scheins unserer Fackel scheinen eigenständig zu wachsen und zu schrumpfen.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_17"><![CDATA[Meine Ängste haben sich bestätigt! Unsere Fackel wurde von einem Spritzer Seewasser gelöscht, und wir gerieten in einen Hinterhalt! Seltsame, fischartige Kreaturen griffen uns in der plötzlichen Dunkelheit an! Das Pech der Fackel fing schnell wieder Feuer, und ich erblickte schuppige Gliedmaßen, die primitive, mit Stacheln versehene und im Fackelschein glitzernde Waffen schwangen. Bei brennender Fackel hatten sie uns wenig entgegenzusetzen. Doch eins dieser Wesen biss mir in den Hals, bevor ich es ausweiden konnte. Die Wunde sticht und kitzelt auf seltsame Weise. Unser Heilkundler sagte, ich solle sie säubern und bedeckt halten ...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_18"><![CDATA[Die Wunde fängt an zu eitern. Das Fleisch um sie herum ist grau, schuppig und gefurcht – fast wie bei Fischen. Während ich dies schreibe, klingt mein Atem hohl und es fällt mir schwer, Luft zu holen. Meine Kameraden lachen und sagen mir, ich solle mir keine Sorgen machen ... es sei nur der salzige Dunst, der diese Höhlen durchdringt.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_19"><![CDATA[Sie schlafen. Ein stetiges Geflüster hält mich wach, das von den Strömungen und Wellen der See getragen zu sein scheint. Ich habe ihnen nicht gesagt, dass ein Großteil meiner Haut sich abgelöst hat und eine seltsame, silbrige Membran freigelegt hat. Ich halte mich bedeckt. Am Lager fragten sie mich, warum ich das Fleisch roh äße, und hatten Schwierigkeiten, meiner Antwort zu folgen. Wahrscheinlich sollte ich ihnen meinen Zustand erklären, wenn sie erwachen ... dann würden sie einsehen, warum ich so dringend gehen und im Dorf Hilfe suchen möchte.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_20"><![CDATA[Die anderen sind tot. Sie wurden Opfer einer bösartigen Verwandlung! Ihre Schuppen waren verfault und hatten weiches, verletzliches Fleisch freigelegt. Ohne Kiemen erstickten sie langsam! Das Schlimmste waren ihre Augen! Sie lagen nah beieinander und waren gezwungen, durch fleischige Schlitze zu blinzeln! Ich erinnere mich an die schreckliche und unreine Wärme ihres Blutes, als ich meine Klauen reinigte. Ich hätte mich fast übergeben. Möge der Tod ihnen sanfte Gnade erweisen!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_21"><![CDATA[Ich weiß nicht mehr, warum wir an Land gingen. Warum verließen wir Mutter Ozean, die unter ihren sanften Wellen alles gewährte, was wir brauchten? Ich werde nun heimkehren, zurück in ihre Arme ... [Der Rest der Seite ist mit nicht entzifferbarem Gekritzel gefüllt.]]]></entry>
  </language>
  <language id="spanish">
    <entry id="str_inventory_title_journal_page"><![CDATA[Página de diario]]></entry>
    <entry id="str_inventory_description_journal_page"><![CDATA[Un fragmento del diario de una expedición condenada.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_0"><![CDATA[Una nota extraña, escrita sobre carne humana.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_0"><![CDATA[Examinas el trozo de carne desgarrada, apesta a sudor y lágrimas. Una serie de crudos boquetes en la piel palpitan y supuran sangre. ¡Parecen formar un patrón! Solo logras entender lo siguiente: «¡Aquí en Red Hook Games, estamos enormemente agradecidos por tu apoyo y el tiempo que has pasado en la mazmorra oscura! Buena suerte en la próxima batalla...»]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_1"><![CDATA[Diario de Darius, bandolero (1/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_2"><![CDATA[Diario de Darius, bandolero (2/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_3"><![CDATA[Diario de Darius, bandolero (3/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_4"><![CDATA[Diario de Darius, bandolero (4/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_5"><![CDATA[Diario de Darius, bandolero (5/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_6"><![CDATA[Diario de Darius, bandolero (6/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_1"><![CDATA[Día 1. Raro es ver viajeros por estos caminos en otoño y, antes que morirme de hambre, he dado mi última moneda a alguien que ofrecía rumores y sombras. Los cuervos llevaban notas crípticas en las que decían que había una persona, o personas, que estaban prometiendo dinero a cambio de servicios que es mejor no mencionar, en un poblado del que nunca he oído hablar. Preparo mi mochila y parto inmediatamente.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_2"><![CDATA[Día 4. El camino a este poblado ha sido complicado, tanto de encontrar como de atravesar. Cuando ha revelado su rostro en ruinas... Jamás había visto tal abandono, algunos edificios estaban derruidos y los habitantes se mostraban inquietos, aunque indiferentes. Me he dirigido rápidamente a la taberna; otros con intereses similares se habían reunido allí y me he unido a una expedición. Partiremos mañana al amanecer.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_3"><![CDATA[Día 6. Al salir del poblado, un temor espeluznante se ha ido apoderando de nosotros. Todos lo hemos sentido, pero hemos hecho lo posible por zafarnos de él. Dormir ha sido difícil hasta que Raeven, uno de mis compañeros, me ha pasado un mejunje amargo. El más devoto de nosotros, Therion, ha rezado en voz baja por nuestra seguridad, de forma supersticiosa pero bien intencionada, supongo. Me estoy quedando dormido...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_4"><![CDATA[Día 7. Nos topamos con unos tipos muy agitados. Raeven los ha llamado cultistas. Parecían feroces pero torpes.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_5"><![CDATA[Día 8. Moira ha estado enferma, debe de haber sido por culpa del aire podrido de un ataúd que se empeñó en perforar con la pala. Por muy terrible que sea este lugar, sé que no caeré en ninguna trampa ni en el engaño de ningún idiota chiflado. Me apuesto mi moneda de la suerte.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_6"><![CDATA[Mi fin. Garabateo esto, víctima de la cruel Fortuna, con la que aposté y perdí mi moneda de la suerte, pues ahora yazco indefenso mientras la sangre me brota rápidamente de un cuerpo maltrecho. Tengo los dedos fríos... No fue ninguna trampa, ni ningún cultista delirante quien selló mi destino. Nos tendieron una emboscada unas formas ondulantes, dos pequeños entes que no puedo describir y una tercera bestia, mucho más grande. Pobre Moira, que fue aplastada y convertida en una masa mientras Therion la defendía. Él también perdió el brazo, y la razón. «¡Destructor! ¡Destructor!», no paraba de gritar mientras Raeven tiraba de él tratando de huir. Intenté hacerme el héroe para ganar algo de tiempo... Maté a uno de los monstruos más pequeños... El último disparo... Luego aplasté contra el muro... al grande... tal vez consiguieron escapar...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_7"><![CDATA[El más negro destino (1/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_8"><![CDATA[El más negro destino (2/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_9"><![CDATA[El más negro destino (3/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_10"><![CDATA[El más negro destino (4/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_11"><![CDATA[El más negro destino (5/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_7"><![CDATA[Nuestro objetivo era profanar sus santuarios animalistas y así dispersar a las bestias porcinas. Pero pronto encontramos un artefacto. Era mucho más que el fetiche tosco que tallaban los hombres cerdo. Parecía una obsidiana que había crecido y se había convertido en un símbolo oscuro y retorcido de veneración. Tenía un orbe rojo palpitante que brillaba con una luz malevolente. Cuthbert, Boleyn y yo dudamos, pero el maldito Mizir, movido por un impulso demente, lanzó su antorcha en un receptáculo oculto y así selló nuestro destino.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_8"><![CDATA[En ese mismo instante nos encontramos en un lugar de una oscuridad sofocante, enfrentándonos a una criatura imposible de describir y cuyo pensamiento hace que mi pluma se estremezca y tiemble. Es misericordioso que solo fragmentos de nuestra batalla permanezcan en mi mente... Veo a Cuthbert cortando los apéndices temblorosos del monstruo. Recuerdo como un trozo de su carne se desmembró y atacó de motu propio a Boleyn, ¡perforándole la robusta armadura! ¡El ocultista, como si se presentara a sí mismo como ofrenda, fue despedazado por las extremidades!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_9"><![CDATA[El asalto fue abrumador. Con Cuthbert muerto y Boleyn caído, la rabia se apoderó de mí. Me abalancé y blandí mi hacha contra los numerosos ojos de la criatura. Una sustancia morada me salpicó la cara y mi propia alma se estremeció mientras bramaba. Lo único que recuerdo después fue que me sumí rápidamente en la negrura.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_10"><![CDATA[Ahora me encuentro de nuevo en el laberinto, junto a los restos de mis compañeros. Mis heridas son demasiado graves como para poder terminar nuestra... mi misión. Así pues, la profanación deberá continuar en otro momento. Curiosamente, llevo un anillo en el bolsillo. No tengo ni idea de dónde procede, aunque lleva el sello del dueño ancestral del feudo. Muy curioso.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_11"><![CDATA[Regresaré con el estandarte de Cuthbert y el arco de Boleyn para rendirles homenaje con un entierro adecuado. Dejaré lo que queda del maldito Mizir y sus abalorios para las bestias porcinas. Tal vez le construyan el monumento que sin duda se merece.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_12"><![CDATA[Un diario pisoteado (1/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_13"><![CDATA[Un diario pisoteado (2/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_14"><![CDATA[Un diario pisoteado (3/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_15"><![CDATA[Un diario pisoteado (4/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_12"><![CDATA[Sebastian ha hecho su última guardia. Nos hemos visto sobresaltados durante la cena, la mejor que hemos podido conseguir en estas salas oscuras de lo que fuera nuestra gran casa, por el rugido y la explosión de la pólvora. Hemos soltado los platos y hemos ido corriendo hacia él, pero solo hemos encontrado su pistola humeante y un rastro de sangre que corría hacia un laberinto de sombras. Seguimos avanzando.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_13"><![CDATA[Hemos luchado hasta la muerte en la galería oriental, repleta de retratos de nuestro antiguo linaje, contra unos enemigos indiferentes. Alhazred, el más ardiente de nuestro séquito, ha sembrado el caos entre las filas enemigas. Siento profundamente su ausencia incluso al recordar el vacío vivido al ver caer su cuerpo sin vida, con la sangre brotándole por la boca mientras gritaba después de que un cruel cuchillo le atravesara los pulmones. Aun así, hemos salido victoriosos y seguimos avanzando.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_14"><![CDATA[Hewell, estimado amigo, guerrero ejemplar, superviviente de las guerras del rey y de muchas incursiones en estas salas, ha terminado de un modo tremendamente innoble. Estábamos cansados, Hewell y yo, mientras buscábamos el santuario. El cansancio, al parecer, tiene un lado asesino: no ha visto el mecanismo y ha pisado unos pinchos que han acabado con su vida. Lo he sostenido mientras su esencia se escurría, otro gigante caído en nuestra loca misión. Ahora estoy solo, cansado, pero incólume. Sigo avanzando.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_15"><![CDATA[¡ME HE CONVERTIDO EN LA VENGANZA! ¡Todos los cultistas conocerán mi mazo, todos los forajidos temerán mi rugido! Ahora me superan en número, es cierto, estoy hambriento y medio loco, pero mientras haya aliento en mi cuerpo, continuaré. ¡Les provocaré una agonía insoportable a quienes traten de despojarme de mi casa! ¡Y aquí vienen! He apagado la antorcha. ¡NO TEMO A LA OSCURIDAD! ¡ESTA ES MI CASA, Y POBRES DE QUIENES VENGAN SIN SER INVITADOS!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_16"><![CDATA[Páginas de un diario empapadas de sangre (1/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_17"><![CDATA[Páginas de un diario empapadas de sangre (2/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_18"><![CDATA[Páginas de un diario empapadas de sangre (3/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_19"><![CDATA[Páginas de un diario empapadas de sangre (4/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_20"><![CDATA[Páginas de un diario empapadas de sangre (5/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_21"><![CDATA[Páginas de un diario empapadas de sangre (6/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_16"><![CDATA[Estas cuevas oscuras rezuman un exceso de humedad que supera el umbral de la comodidad. Casi me rompo el tobillo en las rocas, resbaladizas con una especie de cieno ubicuo. Los estanques se arremolinan y chapotean sin causa visible y las sombras más allá de la luz de la antorcha parecen crecer y encogerse por sí solas.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_17"><![CDATA[¡Mis temores están confirmados! Mientras nuestra antorcha se apaga con una inesperada ola de agua marina, ¡nos tienden una emboscada! ¡Unos extraños homínidos con forma de pez nos asaltan en la repentina oscuridad! La brea de la antorcha se ha recuperado rápidamente y he podido ver extremidades con escamas blandiendo toscas armas, brillantes y mordaces. No han durado mucho, al avivarse nuestra antorcha completamente. Pero, ay, uno me ha golpeado en el cuello antes de destrozarlo en pedazos. La herida me escuece y me pica de una forma extraña. Nuestro médico me ha dicho que la mantenga limpia y tapada...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_18"><![CDATA[La herida está empezando a supurar. La carne de alrededor se ha puesto gris, está descamada y agrietada, casi como una escama. Mientras escribo esto mi respiración ha adoptado un timbre hueco y se ha vuelto entrecortada. Mis compañeros se ríen y dicen que no me preocupe, que es simplemente la neblina salina que inunda estas cavernas.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_19"><![CDATA[Están durmiendo. Yo me mantengo despierto por culpa de un flujo nítido de susurros, como si fueran transportados por las corrientes y las olas del mar. No les he dicho que casi toda la carne se me ha caído para dejar ver una extraña membrana plateada. La mantengo tapada. Me han preguntado cuándo me comí la carne cruda en el campamento y han visto que mi respuesta era difícil de entender. Supongo que será mejor explicar mi condición cuando se despierten, entonces estarán convencidos de que debo marchar y buscar ayuda urgentemente en el poblado.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_20"><![CDATA[Los demás se han ido. ¡Han sufrido una transformación malévola! Sus escamas se habían podrido hasta convertirse en carne blanda y vulnerable. ¡Lentamente, sofocándose sin branquias! ¡Lo peor fueron los ojos! ¡Cerrados y obligados a mirar por unas rendijas carnosas! Me estremezco al recordar la horrible y sucia calidez de su sangre mientras me enjuagaba las garras. Casi vomito. ¡Que la Muerte se apiade de ellos!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_21"><![CDATA[No recuerdo por qué nos aventuramos a tierra firme. ¿Por qué nos marchamos cuando la Madre Océano nos proporcionaba todo lo que necesitábamos al amparo de sus delicadas olas? Ahora regresaré a casa, volveré a Su abrazo... [unos garabatos indescifrables llenan el resto de la página].]]></entry>
  </language>
  <language id="brazilian">
    <entry id="str_inventory_title_journal_page"><![CDATA[Página de Diário]]></entry>
    <entry id="str_inventory_description_journal_page"><![CDATA[Extrato de um diário de uma expedição condenada.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_0"><![CDATA[Uma estranha anotação, escrita em pele humana sangrenta.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_0"><![CDATA[Você examina o pedaço lacerado de pele. Ele cheira a suor e lágrimas. Uma série de sulcos grosseiros na pele pulsam e expelem sangue. Eles parecem formar um padrão! Você só consegue compreender o seguinte: "Nós, da Red Hook Games, estamos muito agradecidos pelo seu apoio e dedicação ao Darkest Dungeon! Boa sorte em suas batalhas futuras..."]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_1"><![CDATA[Diário de Darius, Bandido (1/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_2"><![CDATA[Diário de Darius, Bandido (2/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_3"><![CDATA[Diário de Darius, Bandido (3/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_4"><![CDATA[Diário de Darius, Bandido (4/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_5"><![CDATA[Diário de Darius, Bandido (5/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_6"><![CDATA[Diário de Darius, Bandido (6/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_1"><![CDATA[Dia 1 - Os viajantes são raros nas estradas neste outono. Em vez de passar fome, investi minha última moeda com uma pessoa que lida com boatos e sombras. Os corvos trouxeram notícias sinistras, dizendo que havia uma pessoa, ou pessoas, oferecendo moedas por serviços não mencionados numa aldeia da qual jamais ouvira falar. Estou me dirigindo para lá imediatamente.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_2"><![CDATA[Dia 4 - O caminho para esta aldeia maldita é traiçoeiro, tanto para encontrar quanto para percorrer. Quando ela finalmente se revelou, juro nunca ter visto tamanha negligência. Alguns edifícios tinham desmoronado e habitantes indiferentes vagavam ociosamente. Fui direto para a taverna. Outras pessoas com interesses parecidos haviam se reunido lá e eu fui aceito numa expedição. Vamos partir à primeira luz da manhã.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_3"><![CDATA[Dia 6 - Enquanto saíamos da aldeia, um medo sinistro começou a crescer. Todos nós podíamos senti-lo, mas fizemos o possível para ignorá-lo. O sono era difícil até que Raeven, um de meus companheiros, me passou uma bebida amarga. O mais devoto de nós, Therion, rezou baixo por nossa segurança, supersticioso mas bem intencionado, suponho. Já estou quase caindo no sono...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_4"><![CDATA[Dia 7 - Pelejamos com um bando de figuras malditas. Raeven os chamou de cultistas. Eles eram ferozes, mas desajeitados.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_5"><![CDATA[Dia 8 - Moira está doente por causa do ar nauseabundo vindo de um caixão que ela insistiu em perfurar com sua pá. Este lugar é terrível e eu não vou cair numa armadilha como um idiota. Aposto minha moeda da sorte nisto.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_6"><![CDATA[Meu fim - Rabisco estes escritos, vítima de um destino cruel que me venceu na minha aposta. Perdi minha moeda da sorte e agora estou deitado, indefeso, sobre o meu próprio sangue que corre pelo meu corpo arruinado. Meus dedos estão frios… Não foi uma armadilha, nem um cultista fanático quem decretou a minha condenação. Fomos emboscados por formas ondulantes, 2 pequenas entidades que nem tentarei descrever e uma terceira fera bem maior. A pobre Moira foi esmagada enquanto Therion tentava defendê-la. Logo ele perdeu seu braço e também seu juízo. “Cambaleante! Cambaleante!”, ele gritava enquanto Raeven o puxava para fugir. Tentei bancar o herói, para dar-lhes alguns segundos... acabei com um dos monstros menores... o último tiro... depois contra a parede... o grande... talvez eles tenham conseguido escapar...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_7"><![CDATA[O Destino mais Sombrio (1/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_8"><![CDATA[O Destino mais Sombrio (2/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_9"><![CDATA[O Destino mais Sombrio (3/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_10"><![CDATA[O Destino mais Sombrio (4/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_11"><![CDATA[O Destino mais Sombrio (5/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_7"><![CDATA[Nosso objetivo era desmanchar seus santuários animalísticos e assim dispersar o povo suíno. Mas logo nos deparamos com um artefato. Era algo muito além dos objetos toscos criados pelos homens-porcos. Parecia feito de obsidiana que havia crescido e torcido num símbolo sinistro de veneração. Ele continha um orbe vermelho pulsante com uma luz maligna. Cuthbert, Boleyn e eu hesitamos, mas o maldito Mizir, controlado por um impulso insano, enfiou sua tocha em um compartimento escondido, o que selou nosso destino!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_8"><![CDATA[Naquele mesmo instante nos encontramos num lugar de escuridão sufocante, frente a uma criatura indescritível e cuja memória faz minha pena saltar e tremer! Tenho sorte de ter guardado apenas fragmentos de nossa batalha na minha mente... Vejo Cuthbert golpeando os apêndices tremulantes de um monstro. Lembro como um pedaço de carne foi cortado mas mesmo assim atacou Boleyn, perfurando sua resistente armadura! O ocultista, como se quisesse se oferecer como sacrifício, foi despedaçado pelos membros descontrolados!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_9"><![CDATA[O ataque foi terrível. Com Cuthbert morto e enquanto Boleyn caía, fui tomado pelo ódio. Saltei e golpeei com o machado entre os muitos olhos da criatura. Um líquido roxo espirrou na minha cara e minha própria alma se abalou enquanto o monstro gritava. A única coisa de que me lembro depois é da escuridão que rapidamente me envolveu.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_10"><![CDATA[Agora me encontro de volta aos labirintos, entre os restos dos meus companheiros. Meus ferimentos são severos demais para que eu conclua a nossa - minha tarefa. Sendo assim, a limpeza terá que ser concluída em uma outra oportunidade. Estranho, há um anel no meu bolso. De onde veio? Não faço ideia, embora ele possua a insignia do dono ancestral da propriedade. Muito curioso.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_11"><![CDATA[Voltarei com o estandarte de Cuthbert e a besta de Boleyn para que tenham um enterro digno. Vou deixar o que restou do maldito Mizir e seus apetrechos para o povo suíno. Talvez eles lhe construam um memorial apropriado.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_12"><![CDATA[Um Diário Pisoteado (1/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_13"><![CDATA[Um Diário Pisoteado (2/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_14"><![CDATA[Um Diário Pisoteado (3/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_15"><![CDATA[Um Diário Pisoteado (4/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_12"><![CDATA[A vigia de Sebastian foi sua última. Fomos surpreendidos durante nossa refeição da noite, a melhor que poderíamos fazer nestes salões sombrios da nossa casa que outrora foi grandiosa, com um rugido e fagulha de pólvora negra. Largamos nossos pratos e corremos até ele. Tudo o que conseguimos encontrar foi um rastro de sangue seguindo para um labirinto de sombras. Vamos em frente.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_13"><![CDATA[Lutamos na galeria leste, cheia de retratos de nossa antiga linhagem, testemunhas indiferentes do massacre. Alhazred, o coração flamejante do nosso grupo, causou danos devastadores em nossos inimigos. Sinto sua ausência quando me lembro de seu corpo morto caindo ao chão, sangrando, com uma faca rústica atravessada em seus pulmões. Ainda assim fomos vitoriosos. Prosseguimos.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_14"><![CDATA[Hewell, amigo querido, guerreiro exemplar, um sobrevivente das guerras do rei e de muitos ocorridos nestes salões nefastos, finalmente encontrou o seu fim. Estávamos exaustos, Hewell e eu, enquanto procurávamos por um refúgio. A fadiga tem um aspecto assassino: ela o cegou para o mecanismo cheio de espetos que o massacraram. Tomei-o em meus braços enquanto sua alma se esvaía. Mais um gigante derrotado em nossa busca insana. Estou sozinho agora, cansado, mas decidido. Eu continuo.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_15"><![CDATA[SOU A PRÓPRIA VINGANÇA! Todos os cultistas sentirão a minha maça! Bandidos temerão meu grito! Estou cercado, é verdade - estou faminto e meio louco, mas enquanto houver vida em meu corpo, prosseguirei. Causarei agonia terrível àqueles que querem saquear a minha morada! Eles estão chegando! Eu apago a minha tocha. NÃO TENHO MEDO DA ESCURIDÃO! ESTA É A MINHA CASA E EU CONDENO AQUELES QUE NÃO FORAM CONVIDADOS!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_16"><![CDATA[Páginas Encharcadas de Sangue de um Diário (1/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_17"><![CDATA[Páginas Encharcadas de Sangue de um Diário (2/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_18"><![CDATA[Páginas Encharcadas de Sangue de um Diário (3/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_19"><![CDATA[Páginas Encharcadas de Sangue de um Diário (4/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_20"><![CDATA[Páginas Encharcadas de Sangue de um Diário (5/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_21"><![CDATA[Páginas Encharcadas de Sangue de um Diário (6/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_16"><![CDATA[Nestas cavernas sombrias a umidade pinga abundantemente, além do limite do meu conforto. As poças espirram e ondulam sem nenhuma causa e as sombras além da luz da tocha parecem aumentar e diminuir segundo sua própria vontade.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_17"><![CDATA[Meus medos foram confirmados! Com nossa tocha apagada por um inesperado jorro de água do mar, fomos emboscados! Humanoides com feições de peixe nos surpreenderam da repentina escuridão! A tocha se reacendeu rapidamente e percebi membros escamosos manuseando armas toscas, cintilantes e espinhosos. Eles não duraram muito com nossa tocha ardendo novamente. O ferimento dói e coça de maneira estranha. Nosso médico me disse para mantê-lo limpo e coberto...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_18"><![CDATA[O ferimento está infeccionando. A pele ao redor está cinza, escamada e endurecida. Enquanto escrevo estas palavras, minha respiração toma um timbre oco e requer mais esforço. Meus companheiros estão rindo e me dizem para eu não me preocupar: é apenas a névoa salgada que impregna estas cavernas.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_19"><![CDATA[Eles estão dormindo. Não consigo adormecer por causa um coral de murmúrios distintos, carregados pelas correntes e ondas do mar. Não contei a eles que a maioria da minha pele já se foi, revelando uma membrana prateada. Fico sempre coberto. Eles me questionaram quando comi um pedaço de carne crua no acampamento e acharam minha resposta difícil de compreender. Acho que será melhor explicar minha condição quando eles acordarem. Com certeza vão se convencer da minha necessidade de sair desse lugar imediatamente para buscar ajuda na aldeia.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_20"><![CDATA[Todos se foram, vítimas de uma transformação maligna! As escamas deles haviam se tornado uma pele podre, macia e vulnerável. Sufocando rapidamente sem guelras! O pior eram os olhos deles! Limitados, forçados a ficaram semicerrados atrás de membranas de carne! Tremo ao lembrar do seu sangue quente e profano enquanto limpava minhas garras. Que a morte lhes traga descanso e misericórdia!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_21"><![CDATA[Não consigo me lembrar por que andávamos sobre a terra. Por que deixamos o Pai Oceano quando ele nos fornece tudo de que precisamos sob suas ternas ondas? Voltarei agora para casa. De volta para seu abraço… [arranhões indecifráveis preenchem o resto da página].]]></entry>
  </language>
  <language id="russian">
    <entry id="str_inventory_title_journal_page"><![CDATA[Страница из дневника]]></entry>
    <entry id="str_inventory_description_journal_page"><![CDATA[Выдержка из дневника участника обречённого похода.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_0"><![CDATA[Странная запись на кровавой человечьей плоти.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_0"><![CDATA[Вы изучаете рваный кусок плоти, воняющий потом и слезами. На коже пульсируют глубокие кровоточащие борозды, которые, кажется, складываются в узор! Вы можете разобрать лишь следующее: "Мы, работники Red Hook Games, сердечно благодарим вас за поддержку и время, потраченное на игру в Darkest Dungeon! Удачи в предстоящей битве..."]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_1"><![CDATA[Дневник разбойника Дариуса (1/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_2"><![CDATA[Дневник разбойника Дариуса (2/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_3"><![CDATA[Дневник разбойника Дариуса (3/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_4"><![CDATA[Дневник разбойника Дариуса (4/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_5"><![CDATA[Дневник разбойника Дариуса (5/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_6"><![CDATA[Дневник разбойника Дариуса (6/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_1"><![CDATA[День 1. Этой осенью путников на дорогах мало, и вместо того, чтобы голодать, я отдал последнюю монету тому, кто знает о слухах и тенях. Вороны принесли загадочные вести о том, что в неизвестном мне городе есть человек, или люди, которые платят за услуги, о коих лучше не упоминать. Собираю вещи и немедленно выдвигаюсь.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_2"><![CDATA[День 4. Дорога в этот город была непростой: еле нашёл, и еле прошёл. Наконец, я всё же добрался до этих развалин... Клянусь, в жизни не видел такого запустения! Некоторые дома разрушены, а их жители бесцельно крутятся поблизости. Я быстро нашёл трактир, где собрались и другие путники со схожими намерениями, и теперь меня даже взяли в поход. Выходим завтра на рассвете.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_3"><![CDATA[День 6. Стоило покинуть город, как на нас напал какой-то непонятный страх. Всем было не по себе, но мы, как могли, старались стряхнуть с себя это ощущение. Я не мог спать, пока Рэвен, один из спутников, не дал мне какого-то горького зелья. Самый набожный из нас, Терион, тихо молился за наше благополучие – я в такое не верю, ну да не помешает. Вот я, кажется, и засыпаю...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_4"><![CDATA[День 7. Подрались с какими-то буйными дуралеями. Рэвен сказал, что это были сектанты. Дрались отчаянно, но не слишком умело.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_5"><![CDATA[День 8. Мойра подхватила какую-то заразу. Думаю, она была в гадком воздухе, что вырвался из гроба, который ей позарез надо было пробить лопатой. В таком жутком месте надо быть начеку! Я не попадусь ни в ловушку, ни в лапы безумцев. Готов поставить на это свою счастливую монетку.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_6"><![CDATA[Вот мне и конец пришёл. Пока могу, пишу о своей несчастной судьбе... Видать, судьба приняла мою ставку, и я проиграл, ибо я потерял свою счастливую монетку, и теперь, покалеченный, беспомощно лежу здесь, истекая кровью. Пальцы леденеют... Но прикончила меня не ловушка и не безумный сектант. На нас напали из засады странные колышущиеся фигуры: две мелкие, которые я не могу описать, и одна большая тварь. Бедную Мойру просто раздавило, а Терион, пытавшийся защитить её, скоро лишился руки и сошёл с ума. Он всё кричал: "Тьманник, тьманник!", а Рэвен оттаскивал его. Я попытался погеройствовать, дать им время отбежать... Последним выстрелом убил мелкую тварь, а потом меня швырнуло об стену... большая тварь... может, они убежали...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_7"><![CDATA[Чернейшая из судеб (1/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_8"><![CDATA[Чернейшая из судеб (2/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_9"><![CDATA[Чернейшая из судеб (3/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_10"><![CDATA[Чернейшая из судеб (4/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_11"><![CDATA[Чернейшая из судеб (5/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_7"><![CDATA[Нашей задачей было осквернить зверосвятилища и обратить свинолюдей в бегство. Но вскоре мы набрели на артефакт намного более искусный, чем примитивные творения свинолюдей. Было похоже, что обсидиан будто бы вырастили и скрутили в тёмный священный символ. Внутри него был пульсирующий красный шар, светящийся недобрым светом. Катберт, Болейн и я колебались, но трижды проклятый Мизир, движимый безумным порывом, ткнул факелом в потайное отверстие и тем самым решил всё за нас!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_8"><![CDATA[Мы тотчас оказались в непроглядной тьме, лицом к лицу с тварью, которую невозможно даже начать описывать, и одно воспоминание о которой заставляет моё перо дрожать! Хорошо, что память сохранила лишь обрывки того сражения... Помню, как Катберт рубил колыхающиеся придатки чудища. Помню, как отрубленный кусок его плоти отлетел, а затем неведомой силой прыгнул на Болейна и проткнул его надёжную броню! Оккультист же, будто решив принести себя в жертву, был разорван на части корчащимися конечностями чудовища.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_9"><![CDATA[Бой был просто невозможным. Катберта убило, Болейн тоже пал, так что остался лишь я, движимый исключительно гневом. Я прыгнул и ударил топором по многочисленным глазам чудовища. В лицо мне хлынула фиолетовая слизь, и тварь взревела так, что сама моя душа содрогнулась. Затем я помню лишь, как быстро погрузился во тьму...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_10"><![CDATA[Теперь я опять в заповеднике, возле останков моих товарищей. Раны мои слишком глубоки, и наше... то есть, моё задание уже не выполнить. Осквернение придётся отложить. Что интересно, у меня в кармане нашлось кольцо... Не представляю, откуда оно взялось там, но на нём есть знак давнего владельца этого имения. Занятно...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_11"><![CDATA[Вернусь с флагом Катберта и с арбалетом Болейна, чтобы достойно похоронить их. А то, что осталось от трижды проклятого Мизира и его барахла, я оставлю свинолюдям. Может, они установят ему памятник, который он по праву заслужил.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_12"><![CDATA[Истоптанный дневник (1/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_13"><![CDATA[Истоптанный дневник (2/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_14"><![CDATA[Истоптанный дневник (3/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_15"><![CDATA[Истоптанный дневник (4/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_12"><![CDATA[Себастьян не вернулся из караула. Мы ужинали, как вдруг по залам этого некогда великого дома разнёсся жуткий рёв, а затем прозвучал выстрел. Побросав миски, мы поспешили к Себастьяну, но нашли только его пистолет и кровавый след, ведущий во тьму. Идём по нему.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_13"><![CDATA[Мы сражались в восточной галерее, а многочисленные портреты наших предков равнодушно наблюдали за кровопролитием. Алхазред, пламенное сердце нашей дружины, отправил на тот свет немало врагов. Я остро ощущаю его отсутствие, и помню, как обмочился, когда его безжизненное тело упало наземь с предсмертным воплем, вырывающимся из окровавленного рта, потому что какой-то злодей ножом пропорол его лёгкие. Но всё же мы победили, и движемся дальше.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_14"><![CDATA[Хивелл, добрый друг, примерный боец, прошедший королевские войны и множественные стычки в этих залах, встретил свой печальный конец. Мы вдвоём искали святилище и порядком устали. Как оказалось, усталость может лишить жизни: Хивелл не заметил механизма, который выпустил шипы, пронзившие моего товарища. Он медленно умирал у меня на руках, ещё один исполин, павший в этой безумной погоне... Теперь я остался один, измученный, но не сломленный. Я иду дальше.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_15"><![CDATA[Я САМ СТАЛ ОТМЩЕНИЕМ! Все сектанты отведают моей палицы, а бандиты испугаются моего рёва! Их намного больше, что правда, то правда, а ещё я истощён и почти сошёл с ума. Но я буду идти вперёд до последнего вздоха, и тех, кто осмелился осквернить мой великий дом, ждут невыносимые муки. А вот и они! Пора гасить факел. Я НЕ БОЮСЬ ТЬМЫ! ЭТО МОЙ ДОМ, И ГОРЕ НЕЗВАНЫМ ГОСТЯМ!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_16"><![CDATA[Вырванные и окровавленные страницы дневника (1/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_17"><![CDATA[Вырванные и окровавленные страницы дневника (2/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_18"><![CDATA[Вырванные и окровавленные страницы дневника (3/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_19"><![CDATA[Вырванные и окровавленные страницы дневника (4/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_20"><![CDATA[Вырванные и окровавленные страницы дневника (5/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_21"><![CDATA[Вырванные и окровавленные страницы дневника (6/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_16"><![CDATA[В этих тёмных пещерах слишком высокая влажность, везде капает, что весьма неприятно. Я поскользнулся на камнях, покрытых вездесущей слизью, и чуть было не сломал щиколотку. В водоёмах какое-то движение и всплески, хоть и безо всяких видимых причин, а тени от факела будто растут и уменьшаются сами по себе.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_17"><![CDATA[Сбылись мои худшие ожидания! Случайный всплеск морской воды затушил нам факел, а потом на нас напали из засады! Из тьмы внезапно выскочили странные человекоподобные рыбы; я вновь быстро засветил смоляной факел и успел разглядеть чешуйчатые конечности, машущие грубыми орудиями, блестящими и зазубренными. Свет факела помог нам расправиться с чудовищами, но одно из них успело укусить меня за шею, прежде чем я выпустил ему кишки. Рана щиплет и странно покалывает... Лекарь велел промыть и забинтовать её.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_18"><![CDATA[Рана загноилась, кожа вокруг неё посерела, начала слезать и трескаться, почти как чешуя. Я пишу, а дыхание моё становится всё ниже и тяжелее. Спутники смеются надо мной и просят не волноваться: мол, это всего лишь от морской соли в воздухе, которой в этих пещерах с избытком.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_19"><![CDATA[Все спят. Я же не могу уснуть из-за постоянного шёпота, будто со мной говорит течение и морские волны. Я никому пока не говорил, что с меня сошла кожа, а под ней оказалась странная серебристая мембрана. Всё время кутаюсь. Когда был привал, я съел мясо сырым. Товарищи стали задавать мне вопросы, и ответами моими не удовлетворились. Думаю, когда они проснутся, нужно будет рассказать им о моём состоянии: быть может, тогда они поймут, сколь оно серьёзно, и согласятся поскорее вернуться в город, где я попрошу помощи.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_20"><![CDATA[Остальных больше нет. Они пали жертвой кошмарных изменений! Чешуя их спала, и осталась только мягкая, уязвимая плоть. Без жабр они медленно задыхались. Но хуже всего были их глаза! Они были посажены так близко, и всё время щурились через узкие щёлочки во плоти! До сих пор передёргивает, когда вспоминаю, какой тёплой и омерзительной была их кровь! Еле удалось отмыть от неё когти, чуть не вырвало. Да будет земля им пухом!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_21"><![CDATA[Не припомню, зачем мы пришли на эту землю. Зачем мы покинули Мать Океан, когда всё, что нужно, мы могли найти в её нежных волнах? Но я возвращаюсь домой, назад в её объятия... [остаток страницы испещрён неразборчивыми каракулями].]]></entry>
  </language>
  <language id="polish">
    <entry id="str_inventory_title_journal_page"><![CDATA[Strona z dziennika]]></entry>
    <entry id="str_inventory_description_journal_page"><![CDATA[Fragment dziennika straconej ekspedycji.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_0"><![CDATA[Dziwna notatka napisana na kawałku ludzkiego ciała.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_0"><![CDATA[Przyglądasz się owemu kawałkowi ciała, od którego czuć odór potu i łez. Poznaczony jest pulsującymi, prymitywnie wykonanymi wyżłobieniami, z których sączy się krew. Wydawać by się mogło, że układają się w pewien wzór! Z trudem udaje ci się odczytać wiadomość: „Zespół Red Hook Games jest Ci bardzo wdzięczny za Twoje wsparcie i czas spędzony przy Najmroczniejszym Lochu! Powodzenia w nadchodzącej bitwie...”]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_1"><![CDATA[Dziennik oprycha Dariusa (1/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_2"><![CDATA[Dziennik oprycha Dariusa (2/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_3"><![CDATA[Dziennik oprycha Dariusa (3/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_4"><![CDATA[Dziennik oprycha Dariusa (4/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_5"><![CDATA[Dziennik oprycha Dariusa (5/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_6"><![CDATA[Dziennik oprycha Dariusa (6/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_1"><![CDATA[Dzień 1. Podróżni z rzadka trafiają się jesienią na tych drogach, a ja, zamiast umrzeć z głodu, wolałem wcisnąć swą ostatnią monetę w dłoń temu, który nasłuchuje pogłosek i wypatruje cieni. Kruki dostarczyły wiadomości, z których wynikało, że w nieznanej mi osadzie znaleźć można osobę lub grupę, która płaci złotem za usługi, o których lepiej nie wspominać. Pakuję się, aby jak najszybciej wyruszyć w drogę.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_2"><![CDATA[Dzień 4. Droga do tej przeklętej osady była trudna do znalezienia i nieprzyjemna w podróży. Przysięgam, nigdy nie widziałem miejsca tak zaniedbanego jak to, które ukazało mi wówczas swe zrujnowane oblicze. Niektóre budynki już się zawaliły, a zobojętniali mieszkańcy błąkali się między nimi bez celu. Skierowałem swe kroki prosto do oberży – zebrali się tam ludzie, którzy szukali tego samego, co ja. Dołączyłem do ich ekspedycji. Ruszamy jutro o świcie.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_3"><![CDATA[Dzień 6. Po opuszczeniu osady zaczął w nas narastać przedziwny lęk. Odczuwaliśmy go wszyscy, lecz robiliśmy co w naszej mocy, żeby się nim nie przejmować. Sen nie przychodził łatwo, dopóki Raeven, jeden z moich towarzyszy, nie podał mi gorzkiej mikstury. Najbardziej pobożny spośród nas, Therion, modlił się spokojnie o nasze bezpieczeństwo. To przesądne, ale zakładam, że wynikało z dobrych intencji. Morzy mnie już sen...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_4"><![CDATA[Dzień 7. Posiekliśmy się z jakimiś niesfornymi ciurami. Raeven nazwał ich okultystami. Byli zaciekli, lecz niezdarni.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_5"><![CDATA[Dzień 8. Moira zapadła na jakąś chorobę, z pewnością przez to przegniłe powietrze z trumny, którą uparła się przebić swą szpadą. Wiem, że na przekór wszystkim koszmarom tego miejsca nie dam się ukatrupić żadnej pułapce i żadnemu obłąkanemu głupcowi. Stawiam na to swoją szczęśliwą monetę.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_6"><![CDATA[Mój koniec – piszę to ja, ofiara złego losu, który wygrał ze mną zakład po tym, jak zgubiłem swą szczęśliwą monetę. Leżę tu bez siły i czuję, jak krew uchodzi z mego zniszczonego ciała. Moje palce są zimne... To nie pułapka i nie rozjuszeni okultyści przypieczętowali mój los. Zaatakowały nas dziwne, falujące kształty, dwa małe stwory, których nie potrafię opisać, wraz z trzecią, znacznie większą bestią. Biedna Moira została zmiażdżona mimo starań Theriona, którego rozum opuścił chwilę po tym, jak stracił rękę. „Wałęsak! Wałęsak!” zawył, gdy Raeven chciał zmusić go do ucieczki. Próbowałem zgrywać bohatera, zyskać nieco na czasie... ostatnim strzałem udało mi się dosięgnąć jednej z mniejszych poczwar... a potem ta ogromna rzuciła mną o ścianę... może udało im się uciec...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_7"><![CDATA[Najczarniejszy z losów (1/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_8"><![CDATA[Najczarniejszy z losów (2/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_9"><![CDATA[Najczarniejszy z losów (3/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_10"><![CDATA[Najczarniejszy z losów (4/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_11"><![CDATA[Najczarniejszy z losów (5/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_7"><![CDATA[Naszym celem było zbezczeszczenie zwierzęcych kapliczek knurzego ludu, co pozwoliłoby nam rozproszyć tych diablich synów. Dość prędko natknęliśmy się na artefakt. Nie miał nic wspólnego z prostymi fetyszami skleconymi przez świniopodobnych. Wyglądał, jakby obsydian wyrósł i skręcił się w mroczny symbol kultu. Jego kształt wił się wokół pulsującej, czerwonej kuli, z której wydobywało się złowrogie światło. Cuthbert, Boleyn i ja wahaliśmy się, ale po trzykroć przeklęty Mizir pod wpływem szaleńczego impulsu wepchnął pochodnię w ukryty otwór i przypieczętował nasz los.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_8"><![CDATA[W tym samym momencie znaleźliśmy się w miejscu spowitym odbierającym dech mrokiem, zmuszeni by stawić czoła potworności, której kształt wymyka się ludzkim słowom i na której wspomnienie serce podchodzi mi do gardła! Miłosierny los sprawił, że w moim umyśle ostały się jedynie fragmenty tego boju... Widzę Cuthberta tnącego podrygujące odnóża potwora. Pamiętam, jak kawałek jego cielska odkleił się od reszty i wiedziony własną szatańską wolą wystrzelił w kierunku Boleyn, przebijając jej twardy napierśnik! Okultysta został rozerwany na kawałki przez te wijące się kończyny, jakby chciał złożyć z siebie ofiarę!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_9"><![CDATA[Atak był przytłaczający, lecz po śmierci Cuthberta i Boleyn zaczął kierować mną gniew. Skoczyłem do przodu, a ostrze mego topora utknęło między licznymi ślepiami potwora. Szkarłatny ichor trysnął na mą twarz, a moja dusza zadygotała, gdy to diabelstwo zaryczało. Dalej pamiętam już tylko, jak szybko ogarnął mnie mrok.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_10"><![CDATA[W jakiś sposób ponownie znalazłem się w Norowisku, otoczony szczątkami swoich towarzyszy. Moje rany są zbyt poważne, abym mógł wykonać nasze... moje zadanie. Bezczeszczenie kapliczek będzie musiało poczekać. Co ciekawe, znalazłem w swej kieszeni pierścień. Nie śmiem się nawet domyślać, skąd się tam wziął, lecz wiem, że zdobi go pieczęć właściciela tej posiadłości. Bardzo osobliwe.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_11"><![CDATA[Wrócę tu ze sztandarem Cuthberta i z kuszą Boleyn, aby uczcić ich pamięć, sprawiając im godny pochówek. Po trzykroć przeklętego Mizira i jego błyskotki zostawię knurzemu ludowi. Może postawią mu pomnik, na który zasługuje.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_12"><![CDATA[Podeptany dziennik (1/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_13"><![CDATA[Podeptany dziennik (2/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_14"><![CDATA[Podeptany dziennik (3/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_15"><![CDATA[Podeptany dziennik (4/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_12"><![CDATA[Warta Sebastiana była jego ostatnią. Podczas wieczornego posiłku, najlepszego, jaki udało nam się przyrządzić w tych pogrążonych w mroku korytarzach naszego niegdyś wielkiego domu, poderwał nas łoskot i błysk czarnego prochu. Rzuciliśmy nasze miski, aby pospieszyć mu na ratunek. Na miejscu znaleźliśmy tylko jego pistolet i ślady krwi prowadzące w głąb tego labiryntu cieni. Ruszamy dalej.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_13"><![CDATA[Walczyliśmy we wschodniej galerii, na której ścianach wisiały portrety naszych przodków, obojętnych świadków tej rzezi. Alhazred, gorąca głowa w naszym orszaku, poważnie przetrzebił szeregi wroga. Boleśnie odczuwam jego nieobecność, nawet gdy przypominam sobie, jak splugawiłem swe spodnie na widok jego ciała padającego bez życia na podłogę. Z ust nieszczęśnika lała się krew, a jakiś okrutny nóż zamienił jego płuca w krwawą miazgę. A jednak udało nam się odnieść zwycięstwo, więc maszerujemy dalej.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_14"><![CDATA[Hewell, mój drogi przyjaciel, wyśmienity wojownik, weteran królewskich wojen i wielu potyczek w tych korytarzach, zginął niegodną śmiercią. Obaj byliśmy już wyczerpani i szukaliśmy schronienia. Wyczerpanie, jak się okazuje, może mieć mordercze efekty: nie pozwoliło mu dojrzeć mechanizmu wystrzeliwującego kolce, które go wypatroszyły. Trzymałem biedaka na rękach, gdy konał. Kolejny tytan, z którego uszło życie podczas naszej szaleńczej wyprawy. Zostałem sam, wyczerpany, lecz nieugięty. Maszeruję dalej.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_15"><![CDATA[STAŁEM SIĘ ZEMSTĄ! Wszyscy okultyści poczują mą maczugę, a rozbójnicy będą się trząść słysząc, jak grzmię! Mają przewagę liczebną, to prawda... jestem wygłodzony i na wpół obłąkany, ale dopóki me serce wciąż bije będę maszerował dalej. Sprowadzę piekielne katusze na tych, którzy chcą splądrować mą posiadłość! Nadchodzą! Gaszę pochodnię. NIE BOJĘ SIĘ CIEMNOŚCI! TO MÓJ DOM, BIADA TYM, KTÓRZY PRZYBYLI TU BEZ ZAPROSZENIA!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_16"><![CDATA[Przesiąknięte krwią strony wyrwane z dziennika (1/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_17"><![CDATA[Przesiąknięte krwią strony wyrwane z dziennika (2/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_18"><![CDATA[Przesiąknięte krwią strony wyrwane z dziennika (3/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_19"><![CDATA[Przesiąknięte krwią strony wyrwane z dziennika (4/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_20"><![CDATA[Przesiąknięte krwią strony wyrwane z dziennika (5/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_21"><![CDATA[Przesiąknięte krwią strony wyrwane z dziennika (6/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_16"><![CDATA[Te pogrążone w mroku jaskinie są tak przesycone wilgocią, że zaczyna mi to zdecydowanie przeszkadzać. Niemal złamałem kostkę, gdy poślizgnąłem się na tych pokrytych wszechobecnym śluzem skałach. Woda wiruje i pryska bez widocznego powodu, a cienie poza kręgiem światła rzucanym przez pochodnię wydają się rosnąć i kurczyć się, jakby były obdarzone własną wolą.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_17"><![CDATA[Moje obawy się potwierdziły! Gdy tylko nasze pochodnie zostały przypadkiem spryskane morską wodą, wpadliśmy w zasadzkę! Dziwne istoty, ni to ryby, ni to ludzie, zaatakowały nas pod osłoną ciemności! Smoła na końcu pochodni szybko się zapaliła, pozwalając mi dojrzeć pokryte łuskami kończyny trzymające prymitywny oręż, lśniący i pokryty kolcami. Nie były w stanie stawić nam czoła, gdy pochodnia zapłonęła ponownie. Niestety, jedna z nich ugryzła mnie w szyję, zanim wyprułem jej wątpia. Rana piecze i dziwnie swędzi. Nasz medyk kazał mi pilnować, żeby była czysta i opatrzona.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_18"><![CDATA[Rana zaczyna się jątrzyć. Skóra wokół niej jest szara, łuszczy się i pokryła się prążkami, niemal jak u ryby. Pisząc te słowa czuję, że mój każdy kolejny oddech jest coraz płytszy i wymaga większego wysiłku od poprzedniego. Moi towarzysze śmieją się i powtarzają, żebym się nie martwił, że to tylko słona mgła, która otula te jaskinie.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_19"><![CDATA[Śpią już. Ja nie mogę zmrużyć oczu z powodu natarczywego strumienia szeptów, zupełnie jakby niosły je morskie prądy i fale. Nie powiedziałem im, że zgubiłem już prawie całą skórę, pod którą skrywała się dziwna, srebrzysta membrana. Pilnuję, żeby moje ciało było zakryte. Zaczęli zadawać pytania, gdy podczas postoju pożywiłem się surowym mięsem, a moja odpowiedź okazała się trudna do zrozumienia. Najlepiej będzie wyjaśnić im, co się ze mną dzieje, gdy się obudzą. Wtedy z pewnością zrozumieją, dlaczego tak bardzo chcę wyjść na zewnątrz i poszukać pomocy w osadzie.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_20"><![CDATA[Wszyscy odeszli. Padli ofiarą złowrogiej transformacji! Ich gnijące łuski przeistoczyły się w miękkie, wrażliwe mięso. Udusili się powoli, pozbawieni swoich skrzeli! Najgorsze były ich oczy! Blisko osadzone, łypiące na świat przez mięsiste otwory! Drżę na samą myśl o tym, jak przerażająco ciepła i plugawa była ich krew, gdy spłukałem nią swoje szpony. Prawie zwymiotowałem. Oby śmierć miłosiernie się nad nimi ulitowała!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_21"><![CDATA[Nie pamiętam już, dlaczego wyprawiliśmy się na ląd. Dlaczego zostawiliśmy naszą Matkę, nasz Ocean, skoro wszystko czego potrzebujemy, zostało nam już zapewnione pod jej czułymi falami? Wrócę teraz do domu, prosto w jej objęcia... [reszta strony jest podrapana w nieczytelny sposób].]]></entry>
  </language>
  <language id="czech">
    <entry id="str_inventory_title_journal_page"><![CDATA[Stránka deníku]]></entry>
    <entry id="str_inventory_description_journal_page"><![CDATA[Útržek z deníku pojednávajícího o výpravě odsouzené k zániku.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_0"><![CDATA[Zvláštní vzkaz napsaný na krvavém lidském mase.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_0"><![CDATA[Prozkoumáváš rozedraný kus masa, který páchne potem a slzami. Z řady pulsujících děr v kůži prosakuje krev. Zdá se, že tvoří určitý vzor! Člověka hned napadne následující: "My v Red Hook Games jsme nesmírně vděční za vaši podporu a čas, který trávíte v Darkest Dungeon! Hodně štěstí v nadcházejících bitvách..."]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_1"><![CDATA[Deník lupiče Daria (1/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_2"><![CDATA[Deník lupiče Daria (2/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_3"><![CDATA[Deník lupiče Daria (3/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_4"><![CDATA[Deník lupiče Daria (4/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_5"><![CDATA[Deník lupiče Daria (5/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_6"><![CDATA[Deník lupiče Daria (6/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_1"><![CDATA[Den 1. - Letošní podzim není na poutníky na cestách zrovna štědrý a než abych umřel hlady, to jsem radši vtiskl svou poslední zlatku do ruky člověka, co zná kdejaké zvěsti a kdejaký stín. Havrani přinesli snesli šifrované informace o jisté osobě nebo osobách, které slibovaly úplatu za služby, o jakých se v jakési vesnici vůbec nemluví. Tu vesnici jsem dosud neznal. Okamžitě si ale balím svoje saky paky a vyrážím na cestu.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_2"><![CDATA[Den 4. - Cesta do té zpropadené vesnice nebyla nic moc, těžko se hledala a navíc byla rozbitá. Když konečně odhalila svou zničenou tvář, na místě bych odpřisáhnul, že něco tak zanedbaného jsem ještě neviděl. Budovy byly rozpadlé a usedlíci jenom tak bezcílně bloumali. Okamžitě jsem se vydal do krčmy - sešli se tam lidé s podobnými zájmy a podařilo se mi nachomýtnout se k jedné výpravě. Vyrážíme zítra za rozbřesku.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_3"><![CDATA[Den 6. - Po cestě z vesnice se nás začal zmocňovat takový zvláštní strach, který postupně narůstal. Cítili jsme to všichni, ale snažili jsme se jej ze všech sil setřást. Do chvíle, než mi Raeven, jeden z mých souputníků, poslal ten hořký dryák, jsem oka nezamhouřil. Therion, nezbožnější z nás, se tiše modlil za naše duše. Sice je to jenom pověra, ale určitě to myslel dobře. Už na mě jde pomalu spaní...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_4"><![CDATA[Den 7. - Zapletli jsme se s nějakými vzpurnými lumpy. Podle Raevena to byli kultisté. I přes své nasazení byli však úplně bezzubí.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_5"><![CDATA[Day 8 - Moiru postihla zvláštní sklíčenost a onemocněla. Určitě to způsobil ten zahnívající vzduch z rakve, kterou chtěla mermomocí prorazit svým rýčem. Je to tady strašné, ale já vím, že se nestanu obětí žádné pasti ani žádného šíleného idiota. Vsadím na to svou minci pro štěstí.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_6"><![CDATA[Můj konec - Tyto řádky píše oběť kruté Štěstěny, která vyhrála sázku. Ztratil jsem totiž svou minci pro štěstí a nyní jen tak bezmocně ležím a sleduji, jak mi ze zničeného těla vytéká krev. Moje prsty jsou ledové... můj osud nezpečetila žádná past ani žádný šílený kultista. Přepadly nás jakési zvláštní zvlněné tvary, 2 malé bytosti, které ani nedokážu popsat, a pak třetí, mnohem větší nestvůra. Chudák Moira byla rozdrcena na kaši, když se ji snažil Therion bránit - sám však brzy přišel o ruku i o všechen zbylý rozum. „Jatka! Jatka!“, pištěl neustále, když ho Raeven ponoukal, aby utekl. Já se snažil hrát si na hrdinu, abych pro ně získal nějaký čas... jednu z těch menších nestvůr jsem dostal... poslední výstřel... následně rozmáznutí o zeď... toho velkého... možná to zvládli...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_7"><![CDATA[Nejčernější osud (1/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_8"><![CDATA[Nejčernější osud (2/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_9"><![CDATA[Nejčernější osud (3/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_10"><![CDATA[Nejčernější osud (4/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_11"><![CDATA[Nejčernější osud (5/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_7"><![CDATA[Chystali jsme se znesvětit ty jejich animální svatyně, a tím celý ten vepřový lid rozprášit. Zanedlouho jsme však narazili na jistý artefakt. Nešlo o žádný odporný fetiš těch prasečích lidí. Bylo to něco víc. Vypadal, jako kdyby někdo vypěstoval obsidián a ohnul jej do temného náboženského symbolu. Uvnitř byla rudá pulsující koule, ze které vyzařovalo zlé světlo. Cuthbert, Boleyn i já jsme otáleli, jenže toho třikrát zatraceného Mizira popadl záchvat nějakého šílenství a vrazil svou pochodeň do ukryté schránky. Tím náš osud zpečetil!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_8"><![CDATA[V tom okamžiku jsme se ocitli na místě, kde panovala tíživá temnota a čelili jsme nestvůře, kterou slovy ani nelze popsat. Když si ji vybavím, začne se mi třást brk, kterým píši tyto řádky! Jaké milosrdenství, že mi v paměti zůstaly pouze útržky vzpomínek na tuto bitvu... Vidím Cuthberta, jak seká do chvějících se přívěsků té nestvůry. Vzpomínám si, jak se jí odloupl kus masa, který z nějakého zvráceného impulsu sám od sebe vystřelil na Boleyn, jíž prorazil plátovou zbroj! Okultista byl roztržen vedví svými vlastními zmítajícími se končetinami, jako kdyby se chtěl sám obětovat!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_9"><![CDATA[Útok byl mocný. Cuthbert padl, Boleyn stejně tak. Ovládl mě hněv. Přiskočil jsem a ťal svou sekerou do nepřeberného množství očí té nestvůry. Do tváře mi vystříkl fialový mok a ten její křik otřásl mou duší v základech. Jediné, na co si vzpomínám, bylo rychlé pohroužení do temnoty.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_10"><![CDATA[Nyní se nacházím opět v králičích norách mezi ostatky svých společníků. Moje rány jsou příliš vážné na to, abych mohl dokončit náš - svůj úkol. Znesvěcení je třeba odložit na jindy. Zvláštní, v kapse mám nějaký prsten. Kde se tam vzal, to se ani neodvažuji hádat, ačkoli nese pečeť někdejšího majitele panství. To je velmi zvláštní.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_11"><![CDATA[Vrátím se s vlajkou Cuthberta a kuší Boleyn, abych je uctil řádným pohřbem. Ostatky a cetky třikrát zatraceného Mizira ponechám vepřovému lidu. Třeba mu postaví pomník, který si právem zaslouží.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_12"><![CDATA[Pošlapaný deník (1/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_13"><![CDATA[Pošlapaný deník (2/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_14"><![CDATA[Pošlapaný deník (3/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_15"><![CDATA[Pošlapaný deník (4/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_12"><![CDATA[Sebastianovi se jeho hlídka stala osudnou. Když jsme usedli k naší večerní krmi, což bylo to nejlepší, co jsme mohli v ponurých chodbách kdysi slavného domu udělat, nepříjemně nás překvapil jakýsi lomoz a záblesk od střelného prachu. Zahodili jsme svoje misky a pospíchali k němu. Našli jsme však pouze jeho pistoli a krvavou stopu vedoucí do stínového bludiště. Odhodlaně pokračujeme dál.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_13"><![CDATA[Svedli jsme boj ve východní galerii, která byla ověšena portréty našeho prastarého rodu, netečných svědků odehrávajících se jatek. Alhazred, neochvějné srdce naší družiny, s nepřátelskými šiky pěkně zamával. Hodně mi chybí, i když si vybavuji, že jsem odešel poté, co jsem viděl padat jeho bezvládné tělo, poté, co jsem viděl, jak se mu z křičícího hrdla valí krev kvůli kudle, co měl surově zabodnutou v plicích. Přesto jsme ale dokázali zvítězit a odhodlaně pokračujeme dál.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_14"><![CDATA[Hewella, mého drahého přítele, příkladného válečníka, veterána z královských válek, stejně jako mnoho dalších v těchto chodbách, potkal ostudný konec. Já i Hewell jsme byli z toho pátrání po svatyni utahaní. Únava, zdá se, řádí jako černá ruka: kvůli ní si nevšiml mechanismu pro aktivaci bodců, které mu rozpáraly břicho. Držel jsem ho a sledoval, jak z něj pomalu vyprchává život. Naše šílená výprava si vyžádala život dalšího titána. Zbyl jsem už jen já, ale necouvnu. Odhodlaně pokračuji dál.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_15"><![CDATA[JÁ SE POMSTÍM! Všichni kultisté pocítí hněv mého palcátu, lupiči, třeste se, stihne vás totiž můj hněv! Mají početní převahu, to je fakt - a já mám hlad a zachvátilo mě šílenství, nicméně hodlám pokračovat dál až do posledního výdechu. Ti, kteří budou chtít vyplenit mou velkou faru, potká nesnesitelná agónie! Už jdou! Polévám svou pochodeň. NEBOJÍM SE TEMNOTY! TOHLE JE MŮJ DŮM A BĚDA VŠEM NEZVANÝM HOSTŮM!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_16"><![CDATA[Krví nasáklé stránky vytržené z deníku (1/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_17"><![CDATA[Krví nasáklé stránky vytržené z deníku (2/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_18"><![CDATA[Krví nasáklé stránky vytržené z deníku (3/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_19"><![CDATA[Krví nasáklé stránky vytržené z deníku (4/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_20"><![CDATA[Krví nasáklé stránky vytržené z deníku (5/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_21"><![CDATA[Krví nasáklé stránky vytržené z deníku (6/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_16"><![CDATA[V těchto temných jeskyních je tak vlhko, až to není příjemné. Málem jsem si zvrtnul kotník na kamenech, na kterých se usadil kluzký, všudypřítomný sliz. V kalužích to bez zjevné příčiny víří a šplíchá a stíny za pochodní si očividně dělají, co chtějí, protože tu se rozrostou a vzápětí se zase smrsknou.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_17"><![CDATA[Moje obavy se potvrdily! Naši pochodeň uhasila zbloudilá sprška mořské vody - někdo nás přepadl! V náhlé temnotě si na nás počíhali nějací rybí hominidi! Smůla pochodně rychle chytla a díky tomu jsem krátce mohl spatřit šupinaté přívěsky, jakési houpající se primitivní zbraně, které se leskly a byly plné ostnů. Naše znovu vzkříšená pochodeň však dlouho nevydržela. Než se mi jednu z těch stvůr podařilo dorazit, stačila mě kousnout do krku. Ta rána štípe a tak zvláštně svědí. Jeden léčitel mi poradil, ať si ji vyčistím a něčím zakryji...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_18"><![CDATA[Rána začala hnisat. Okolní maso je šedé, odlupuje se a jsou na něm vidět vroubky. Vypadá skoro jako šupiny. V době, kdy píši tyto řádky, se mi utlumil dech a je mnohem namáhavější. Moji kolegové se smějí a říkají mi, ať si nedělám starosti, že to je tou slanou mlhou ve vzduchu, kterou jsou jeskyně prosyceny.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_19"><![CDATA[Všichni spí. Mně ve spánku brání zřetelný šepot. Skoro to vypadá, jako by byl unášen mořskými proudy a vlnami. Neřekl jsem jim, že se mi odloupala většina masa a že se objevila taková zvláštní stříbrná membrána. Jsem celý zahalený. Vyptávali se mě, když jsem v táboře jedl maso v syrovém stavu, ale příliš mou odpověď nepochopili. Myslím, že bych jim měl svůj stav ozřejmit, až se probudí. Jistě je to přesvědčí, že by nebylo od věci vyhledat pro mě ve vesnici první pomoc.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_20"><![CDATA[Ostatní jsou mrtví. Stali se obětí jakési zlé proměny! Jejich šupiny se rozložily na měkké, zranitelné maso. Bez žaber se pomalu udusili! Nejhůř ale dopadly jejich oči! Uzavřely se, takže byli nuceni mžourat skrz masité průřezy! Ještě teď se třesu, když si vzpomenu na to strašlivé a nečisté teplo jejich krve při drhnutí svých spárů. Málem jsem se pozvracel. Nechť s nimi má smrt slitování!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_21"><![CDATA[Nedokážu si vzpomenout, proč jsme se vypravili na souš. Proč jsme odešli, když nám Praotec Oceán pod svými něžnými vlnami poskytl vše potřebné? Nyní se vrátím domů, zpátky do jeho náruče… [zbytek stránky je popsán nerozluštitelnými klikyháky].]]></entry>
  </language>
  <language id="italian">
    <entry id="str_inventory_title_journal_page"><![CDATA[Pagina del Diario]]></entry>
    <entry id="str_inventory_description_journal_page"><![CDATA[Un frammento dal diario di una spedizione condannata.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_0"><![CDATA[Uno strano messaggio, scritto su carne umana insanguinata.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_0"><![CDATA[Esaminate il pezzo di carne strappata, che odora di sangue e lacrime. Una serie di tagli grezzi sulla pelle pulsano e grondano sangue. Sembrano formare un messaggio! A fatica si riesce a leggere quanto segue: "Noi del team di Red Hook Games vi siamo immensamente grati per il vostro supporto e il tempo che avete dedicato a Darkest Dungeon! Buona fortuna nella battaglia che si avvicina..."]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_1"><![CDATA[Diario di Darius, Fuorilegge (1/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_2"><![CDATA[Diario di Darius, Fuorilegge (2/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_3"><![CDATA[Diario di Darius, Fuorilegge (3/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_4"><![CDATA[Diario di Darius, Fuorilegge (4/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_5"><![CDATA[Diario di Darius, Fuorilegge (5/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_6"><![CDATA[Diario di Darius, Fuorilegge (6/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_1"><![CDATA[Giorno 1 - Questo autunno le strade sono percorse da pochi viaggiatori, quindi, invece che morire di fame, ho investito i miei ultimi risparmi in pettegolezzi e sotterfugi. I corvi hanno portato una nota misteriosa, secondo la quale esisteva una persona, o più di una, in grado di offrire dei servizi che è bene non citare. Sto per recarmi in questo borgo di cui non ho mai sentito parlare.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_2"><![CDATA[Giorno 4 - Trovare questo maledetto borgo è stato più difficile del previsto, così come percorrerlo. Ne ho scoperto la vera faccia, una faccia rovinata, negletta, parzialmente distrutta, e gli abitanti sono dei buoni a nulla. La mia prima tappa è stata la taverna, dove altri con interessi simili ai miei stavano organizzando una spedizione a cui ho deciso di partecipare. Partiremo domattina all'alba.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_3"><![CDATA[Giorno 6 - Non appena lasciato il borgo, tutti percepivamo un vago timore, ma cercavamo di ignorarlo. Dormire si rivelava difficile, almeno finché Raeven, un membro della compagnia, non mi ha passato un intruglio amaro. Therion, il più devoto, pregava sottovoce per noi, immagino con buone intenzioni. Sento arrivare finalmente il sonno...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_4"><![CDATA[Giorno 7 - Ci siamo imbattuti in alcuni delinquenti che Raeven ha definito adepti. Erano feroci, ma impacciati.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_5"><![CDATA[Giorno 8 - Moira si è ammalata, probabilmente a causa delle esalazioni provenienti da una bara che ha voluto perforare con la sua vanga. Questo posto è terribile, ma non cadrò in nessuna delle sue trappole e starò alla larga dai folli che lo infestano. Ce la farò, ci scommetto la mia moneta fortunata.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_6"><![CDATA[La mia fine - Riesco solo a scarabocchiare queste ultime parole. Sono vittima del fato avverso, che ha accettato la scommessa e mi ha sottratto la mia moneta fortunata. Il sangue scorre via veloce dal mio corpo inerme e fatto a pezzi. Le dita sono gelide... Non è stata una trappola, né un adepto: delle strane forme ondulate ci hanno teso un agguato, 2 entità impossibili da descrivere e una terza bestia molto più grande. La povera Moira è stata schiacciata nonostante Therion abbia provato a proteggerla, ma anche lui ha perso la speranza, insieme alle braccia. Raeven gli urlava di fuggire, ma lui continuava a ripetere "Disastro! Disastro!" e a niente è servito il mio tentativo di guadagnare tempo... Ho ucciso uno dei mostri più piccoli... ma non avevo più colpi... Allora quello più grande... contro il muro... spero si siano salvati...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_7"><![CDATA[Il più Oscuro dei Destini (1/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_8"><![CDATA[Il più Oscuro dei Destini (2/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_9"><![CDATA[Il più Oscuro dei Destini (3/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_10"><![CDATA[Il più Oscuro dei Destini (4/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_11"><![CDATA[Il più Oscuro dei Destini (5/5)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_7"><![CDATA[Il nostro scopo era quello di dissacrare i loro empi santuari e di disperdere questi uomini-maiali. Presto però ci imbattemmo in un manufatto, chiaramente non realizzato da queste creature. L'ossidiana che lo componeva sembrava ritorta in un oscuro simbolo di culto. Al suo interno, una sfera rossa pulsante irradiava una luce sinistra. Cuthbert, Boleyn e io abbiamo esitato, ma quel maledetto di Mizir, guidato da un impulso malsano, ha conficcato la sua torcia in un'alcova nascosta e ci ha condannato tutti!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_8"><![CDATA[Nello stesso istante ci ritrovammo soffocati dall'oscurità, dinnanzi a una creatura impossibile da descrivere. Il solo ricordo mi fa ancora tremare! Fortunatamente, la mia mente rammenta soltanto dei frammenti della battaglia... Vidi Cuthbert colpire le oscillanti appendici del mostro. Vidi un pezzo della sua disgustosa carne staccarsi e, come animato di vita propria, avventarsi su Boleyn, perforando la sua robusta armatura! L'occultista, come se volesse darsi in sacrificio, fu fatto a pezzi dagli arti che continuavano a contorcersi!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_9"><![CDATA[Non c'era più speranza. Cuthbert era morto, e anche Boleyn ormai era caduta. Fu allora che mi abbandonai alla furia, spiccai un balzo e conficcai la mia ascia in uno dei numerosi occhi della creatura. Un liquame purpureo mi schizzò in faccia e il suo grido di dolore sembrò lacerarmi l'anima. Non ricordo più nulla, perché a quel punto l'oscurità mi avvolse.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_10"><![CDATA[Mi ritrovo nel labirinto, insieme ai resti dei miei compagni. Le mie ferite sono troppo gravi e non mi permetteranno di completare la nostra missione... la mia missione. La dissacrazione dovrà attendere. Strano, c'è un anello nella mia tasca. Non ho idea di come ci sia finito. Porta l'emblema dell'antico proprietario della tenuta. È davvero molto strano...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_11"><![CDATA[Riporterò a casa lo stemma di Cuthbert e la balestra di Boleyn per poterli onorare con una degna sepoltura. Lascerò i resti del dannato Mizir e i suoi averi agli uomini-maiale. Spero possano costruirgli la lapide che si merita.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_12"><![CDATA[Un diario logorato (1/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_13"><![CDATA[Un diario logorato (2/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_14"><![CDATA[Un diario logorato (3/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_15"><![CDATA[Un diario logorato (4/4)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_12"><![CDATA[È stato l'ultimo turno di guardia per Sebastian. Durante la cena, consumata nelle fatiscenti mura di una casata un tempo gloriosa, siamo stati scossi dal boato e dal bagliore della polvere nera. Abbandonati i piatti ci siamo precipitati da lui, ma abbiamo trovato solo la sua pistola e una scia di sangue che ci guidava in un labirinto oscuro. Proseguiamo.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_13"><![CDATA[Abbiamo combattuto nella galleria est, piena dei ritratti dei nostri avi, silenti spettatori di quella strage. Alhazred, il fiero leader del nostro gruppo, portava scompiglio tra i ranghi nemici. Sento ancora la sua mancanza, soprattutto quando ripenso al suo corpo senza vita che cade al suolo, al sangue che sgorga dalla sua bocca, al pugnale crudele affondato nel suo polmone. Eppure ne siamo usciti vincitori, e ora proseguiamo nel labirinto.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_14"><![CDATA[Anche Hewell, un caro amico e un guerriero esemplare, un veterano delle guerre del re e di innumerevoli missioni, è morto penosamente. Eravamo sfiniti, Hewell e io, e cercavamo un rifugio. A quanto pare la stanchezza si allea con l'ingiustizia: gli ha nascosto infatti il meccanismo che faceva scattare gli spuntoni che lo hanno sventrato. L'ho tenuto tra le braccia mentre la sua anima fuggiva, un altro titano caduto nella nostre folle rincorsa. Mi rimangono solitudine e debolezza... ma non posso cedere.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_15"><![CDATA[AVRÒ LA MIA VENDETTA! Tutti gli adepti assaggeranno i miei colpi, i banditi sentiranno i miei ruggiti! È vero, loro sono più numerosi, io ho fame e sto per impazzire, ma finché avrò fiato in corpo proseguirò. Infliggerò sofferenze indicibili a chi oserà saccheggiare la mia nobile casata! Eccoli arrivare! Spengo la torcia. NON HO PAURA DELLE TENEBRE! QUESTA È LA MIA CASA, NESSUNO PUÒ PROFANARLA!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_16"><![CDATA[Pagine insanguinate strappate da un diario (1/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_17"><![CDATA[Pagine insanguinate strappate da un diario (2/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_18"><![CDATA[Pagine insanguinate strappate da un diario (3/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_19"><![CDATA[Pagine insanguinate strappate da un diario (4/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_20"><![CDATA[Pagine insanguinate strappate da un diario (5/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_21"><![CDATA[Pagine insanguinate strappate da un diario (6/6)]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_16"><![CDATA[Queste oscure caverne sono insopportabilmente umide. Ho rischiato di rompermi una caviglia sulle rocce rese scivolose dalla melma che le ricopre quasi interamente. Le pozze si agitano senza nessun intervento esterno e le ombre causate dalla torcia sembrano animate di vita propria.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_17"><![CDATA[I miei timori hanno avuto conferma! Non appena uno schizzo d'acqua ha spento la nostra torcia... siamo stati aggrediti! Degli uomini-pesce ci hanno attaccati nel buio! Ho riacceso subito il fuoco e il bagliore ha rivelato arti ricoperti di squame che brandivano rozze armi, lucide e affilate. Grazie alla luce non abbiamo avuto grossi problemi a sopraffarli, ma uno è riuscito a mordermi sul collo prima che potessi sventrarlo. La ferita fa male e brucia in modo sinistro. Il nostro medico mi ha consigliato di tenerla coperta e pulita...]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_18"><![CDATA[La ferita si sta infettando. La carne intorno è grigia, indurita e spaccata, come squame. Mentre scrivo, il mio respiro ha iniziato ad avere un suono gutturale e si è fatto pesante. I miei compagni ridono e mi dicono di non preoccuparmi, che è solo colpa della nebbia salata che permane queste caverne.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_19"><![CDATA[Stanno dormendo, ma io non trovo pace. Sento distintamente dei sussurri incessanti, come portati dalle onde del mare. Non ho detto loro che la mia pelle è mutata, ricoprendosi di una strana membrana argentata. La tengo ben nascosta. Mi hanno chiesto perché ho mangiato carne cruda al campo e non hanno compreso bene la mia risposta. Immagino sia meglio spiegare l'accaduto non appena si sveglieranno, così capiranno che devo tornare urgentemente al borgo per farmi curare.]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_20"><![CDATA[Non ce l'hanno fatta. Erano vittime di una malevola trasformazione! Le loro squame erano marcite e si erano trasformate in morbida carne rosa. Senza branchie stavano soffocando lentamente! E i loro occhi... ravvicinati e coperti da palpebre! Ancora tremo ricordando l'orrido calore del sangue sporco che fluiva mentre affondavo i miei artigli. Ho quasi vomitato. Che la morte possa portare loro la pace!]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_21"><![CDATA[Davvero non ricordo per quale motivo ci siamo spostati sulla terraferma, abbandonando ciò che Padre Oceano ci aveva donato sotto le sue rassicuranti onde. Sì, tornerò a casa, desidero il Suo abbraccio... [il resto delle pagine è occupato da scarabocchi illeggibili]]]></entry>
  </language>
  <language id="tchinese" />
  <language id="schinese">
    <entry id="str_inventory_title_journal_page"><![CDATA[日志页]]></entry>
    <entry id="str_inventory_description_journal_page"><![CDATA[描述着一次破灭的探险的日记中的一页。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_0"><![CDATA[一段写在血腥的人肉上的奇怪笔记。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_0"><![CDATA[你们检查了这被撕下的肮脏血肉，它不断散发着汗液和泪水的腥气。一些潦草的刻画在皮肤上渗着血并古怪地搏动着。它们似乎正在形成一个图案！你们还算顺利地拼凑出了这句话：“红勾游戏（Red Hook Games）工作室非常感谢您对‘极暗地牢’投入的大量时间与支持厚爱！祝您下一场战斗好运哦……”]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_1"><![CDATA[强盗大流士的日志（1/6）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_2"><![CDATA[强盗大流士的日志（2/6）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_3"><![CDATA[强盗大流士的日志（3/6）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_4"><![CDATA[强盗大流士的日志（4/6）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_5"><![CDATA[强盗大流士的日志（5/6）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_6"><![CDATA[强盗大流士的日志（6/6）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_1"><![CDATA[第1天——这个秋天路上的旅人变得稀少，我饿着肚子把最后的硬币交给了一个消息灵通的人。他的乌鸦带回的隐晦纸条写着，在一个我从未听过的小镇，有一个或一群人在花大价钱请人办事，具体内容不便透露。我马上收拾行李出发了。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_2"><![CDATA[第4天——通往这该死小镇的路真是偏僻曲折；找起来麻烦，要过去更麻烦。当它终于显出庐山真面目时，我发誓我从未见过如此破败凋零的地方。在一些倒塌的建筑之间，心不在焉的居民做着无谓的事。我迅速前往酒馆——其他志同道合的人已经在那里集合了。然后我被编入了一支探险队，我们在次日拂晓出发。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_3"><![CDATA[第6天——当我们穿过这个小镇，一种异样的惊恐在我们之中产生了。我们身心俱颤但尽力摆脱着这种感觉。我辗转反侧，直到我的好同伴瑞文给我了一瓶苦涩的调剂。我们之中最虔诚的人赛润，在我入眠时轻轻地祈求着我们平安无事，这很迷信但我觉得莫名地贴心。我已经快要进入梦乡了……]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_4"><![CDATA[第7天——我们和一些不守规矩的怪人缠斗了一会儿。瑞文对他们嗤之以鼻，称他们“邪教徒”。这些人异乎常人得凶残和狂热，但也挺笨拙的。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_5"><![CDATA[第8天——莫伊拉被病痛折磨着，这一定是在她用铲子撬开棺材时吸入了其中腐败的气体。尽管这个地方是如此糟糕，我决不会因那些所谓的陷阱或那些癫狂的白痴们而死。我以我的幸运币下注。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_6"><![CDATA[我的生命已息——我用手涂抹以书。作为残酷命运的牺牲品，它把我作为赌注带走，因为我已经把我的幸运币弄丢了。现在我就这样无助地躺在这里，任凭血液从我面目全非的身体中缓缓流出。我的指头冰凉……再无陷阱，再无胡言乱语的邪教徒企图诅咒我的命运。我们被怪异、起伏不定的形体所袭击。有两个小的、我难以所述的实体，还有第三个，是一个大得惊人的巨兽。可怜的莫伊拉在赛润保护她前被碾成了肉泥——而赛润也很快地失去了他的手臂和他的胆识，“它跛行着，它蹒跚着！”，当瑞文拽起他逃跑时他就这么一直失神地喃喃傻笑着。而我却不知哪来的勇气逞英雄，为他们争取了一点时间……子弹炸开了其中的一只小的……最后一击……然后被撞进了墙……那只大的……或许他们逃脱……]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_7"><![CDATA[最黑暗的命运（1/5）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_8"><![CDATA[最黑暗的命运（2/5）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_9"><![CDATA[最黑暗的命运（3/5）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_10"><![CDATA[最黑暗的命运（4/5）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_11"><![CDATA[最黑暗的命运（5/5）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_7"><![CDATA[我们任务是摧毁它们粗糙的祭坛，这样猪人就将一哄而散，不再聚集于此地。但是我们很快经过了一个古老造物。这个“祭坛”与猪人搭建的粗制膜拜物差之甚远，它看上去就如同黑曜石为了一个形成一个黑暗的信仰符号而扭曲着生长。它支撑着一个红色的脉动的球体，发着一眼看去就充满邪恶的光。库斯博特、博林和我迟疑着，可就在这时，该千刀万剐的米基尔！他被疯狂冲昏了头，将燃烧的火把刺入“祭坛”来表示他所谓的敬意，也诅咒了我们的命运！]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_8"><![CDATA[就在那一瞬间我们不知怎么就到了一个黑暗得令人窒息的地方，面对着一个我穷尽词语也难能描述的，至今在脑海中令我心思欲裂怪物！理智的帷幕保护了我，只让我的记忆中留下了些许我们战斗的破碎场景。不过我依能想起，那个鬼东西是怎么蜕下一块皮肉，而这块皮肉就这么自己就刺穿了博林的层层铠胄！那个什么“神秘学者”，好似要把自己献祭一般被它起伏扭曲的峰形扯成了碎片！]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_9"><![CDATA[我们完全被压制了。库斯博特与博林先后倒下，我的内心充满了怒火。我全力一跃将我的斧子劈入这怪物的眼睛——许多的眼睛。恶心的紫色脓浆溅了我一脸，我的灵魂则在它咆哮时几近破碎。我最后的记忆是在无尽的黑暗中向下跌落着。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_10"><![CDATA[我如今发现自己倒在肮脏的兽窟间，在我同伴们的遗骸间。我伤势过重，完全不足以完成我们——我的任务。所以这破坏猪人信仰的任务只能等下次完成了。奇怪的是在我的口袋里出现了一枚戒指。这是哪里来的？我毫无头绪，尽管它雕刻着似乎是这片土地拥有者祖辈专用的刻印。真是离奇。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_11"><![CDATA[我将把库斯博特的旗帜与博林的十字弩带回给予薄葬。我将可恶的米基尔的尸骸与他古怪的挂饰留给那些猪人。或许它们会为他今天做出的“贡献”而建造一座纪念碑。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_12"><![CDATA[被践踏的日志（1/4）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_13"><![CDATA[被践踏的日志（2/4）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_14"><![CDATA[被践踏的日志（3/4）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_15"><![CDATA[被践踏的日志（4/4）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_12"><![CDATA[塞巴斯蒂安的怀表就是他的遗物了。我们在就餐时被突袭，本来能在这些原属于我们的黯淡大厅里喘一口气的时候；一切在一声咆哮和一抹黑火药的燃光后变了。我们丢下我们的碗向他冲去，而唯一能够找到的是他用过的手枪与一条通向这迷宫那黑暗阴影深处的血迹。我们继续进发。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_13"><![CDATA[我们在东向的画廊遭遇了战斗；画廊满是我们先祖血脉的肖像画，他们以冷漠的眼神见证着这场屠戮。亚尔哈兹瑞德，我们团队最火热的心脏，冲进敌人的队伍如狼似虎。我为他的陨落感到强烈的痛楚，如同我当时不忍目睹就这样倒下时的他；鲜血从他尖叫着的嘴中喷涌而出，几把冰冷的刀子深深地扎入了他的肺。然而，胜利依旧属于我们，于是我们继续前进。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_14"><![CDATA[赫维尔，我亲爱的老战友，国王战争和在这些走廊中几场袭击的幸存者，却倒在可鄙的诡计之下。我们精疲力竭，赫维尔和我，就在我们寻找一个避难之地时，疲惫，如其所显，揭示了它嗜血的一面：它使赫维尔盲目地踩上了拌子与利刺的机关；机关将他剔得血肉模糊。我在他体液流尽时一直抱着他，又一个巨人倒在我们疯狂的追寻之途中。只剩我一个了，苟延残喘，但是不愿屈服。我要继续。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_15"><![CDATA[我就是复仇之神！！！所有的邪教徒将品尝我的铁锤，匪徒们将在我的怒号中瑟缩！我寡不敌众，真是可笑——我已数日粒米未进，我已经半残半疯，但是只要我还有一口气，我将一直继续。我要把这难忍的痛苦倾泻在那些敢于侵扰我房宅的恶徒身上！哈，他们来了！我熄灭了我的火炬。我才不畏惧这黑暗！！！这是我的房子，那些不受欢迎的东西要倒大霉了！！]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_16"><![CDATA[从日志本撕下的染血一页（1/6）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_17"><![CDATA[从日志本撕下的染血一页（2/6）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_18"><![CDATA[从日志本撕下的染血一页（3/6）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_19"><![CDATA[从日志本撕下的染血一页（4/6）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_20"><![CDATA[从日志本撕下的染血一页（5/6）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_title_21"><![CDATA[从日志本撕下的染血一页（6/6）]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_16"><![CDATA[这些黑暗的洞穴因过度的潮湿不断滴漏着，让我感觉非常不舒服。我几乎在这些湿滑的岩石间扭到了我的脚脖子，那些抬眼即是的黏液使它们更加难以攀爬。那些水洼搅动泼溅，而望去时却空无一物。在火把光芒下的影绰仿佛活了一样，令人不安地生长着、退缩着。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_17"><![CDATA[我的恐惧成真了！我们的火把被突如其来的浪花熄灭——我们被包围了！这些活物有人猿般的特征，但却有一颗鱼的头；这些水栖的恶物在聒噪声中同黑暗一起突然向我们袭来！我一把抓住跌落的火把，在那瞬间我瞥见了带鳞肢体挥舞着的，在波光映衬之下锋利而多刺的简陋武器。它们在我们重新点燃火把后没撑多久。咳，其中有个家伙在我将它开膛破肚之前咬在了我的脖子上。伤口出奇的刺痛。我们的医生让我将之清洗干净后仔细包扎起来……]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_18"><![CDATA[脖子上的伤口开始溃烂了。在腐臭的水潭边，我看到创口周围的血肉发灰起皱，一片片脱落，令人不安地像极了鳞片；就在我写下这些时，我吃力地呼吸着，肺部发着空洞的回响。我的同伴笑着让我不要担心，这只是因为我吸多了弥漫在这些水窟中的盐雾罢了。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_19"><![CDATA[他们都睡着了。而我却因为古怪、低语般的水流声了无睡意，就好像我正被洋流海潮轻轻托起。我没敢告诉他们我伤口周围的组织已腐殒殆尽，而一层奇怪的银色薄膜却显露了出来；我把这些遮得严严实实。他们刚刚还在营火熄灭后惊讶地发现我啃着生肉，而我模糊不清的嗓音不足以回答他们的质问。我觉得等他们醒来之后我最好仔细解释一下我的状况，或许他们就会相信这问题的严重性，离开这个鬼地方，到小镇里寻找援助。]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_20"><![CDATA[其他人都逝世了。他们都是那可怕异变的受害者！他们的鳞因腐败化作了绵软、脆弱的肉。他们因没有鳃窒息着！他们的眼睛犹如噩梦！那被增生的肉帘囚禁，挣扎在阻塞物中奄奄一息的明眸！在洗净手蹼时，萦绕我心头的尽是他们可怕、瘟热的血液……我几乎吐了出来。愿死亡能结束他们长久的苦难！]]></entry>
    <entry id="journal_page_text_21"><![CDATA[我都不记得我们为什么要冒这么大险来到陆地上。大海母亲为我们提供了所需的一切，我们又何苦离开她温柔的波涛？我的同伴们都在折磨与凄苦中安息，我已经无力继续到陆地的征程。现在我要回家，回到大海的怀抱……［纸页剩下的部分满是看不清的划刻痕迹］]]></entry>
  </language>
</root>

